we were in deep trouble at Netflix and
我们在Netflix遇到了很大的麻烦，
we had losses of about $50 million we
亏损了大约5000万美元，
have got to sell this sucker fast Mark
必须尽快卖掉这家公司。马克·
Randol is an American Tech entrepreneur
兰多尔是一位美国科技企业家，他是
the co-founder and first CEO of Netflix
Netflix的联合创始人兼首任CEO，
with a career panning numerous startups
拥有丰富的创业
and Ventures marks expertise and
和风险投资经验，其专业知识、
Innovation leadership and business
创新领导力和商业
strategy is unparalleled August 1997
战略无人能及。1997年8月，
Netflix was founded yes and the reality
Netflix成立了。没错，当时的
is the idea was ridiculous it didn't
想法很荒谬，根本
work nobody would rent DVDs by mail but
行不通——没人会愿意通过邮寄方式租DVD。但
with over 40 years of being an
作为一名拥有40多年经验的
entrepreneur I've learned every idea is
企业家，我明白每个想法一开始都是
bad we just don't know why they're bad
不好的，只是我们不知道它们为什么不好。
yet the important thing is how clever
重要的是，你要足够聪明，才能
can you be to come up with a quick and
找到一种快速且
cheap way to test it for example we
低成本的测试方法。例如，我们当时
thought let's just have a subscription
想，不如就推出订阅服务，
and no late fees it was a ridiculous
不收取滞纳金。这听起来很荒谬，
idea but when we tested it people loved
但测试之后，人们非常喜欢。Netflix的
it the Netflix DVD service has changed
DVD租赁服务改变了
the world you explored selling Netflix
世界。在Netflix
to Amazon 2 years after you'd launched
上线两年后，你曾考虑过以
for probably 10 to15 million that's not
1000万到1500万美元的价格将其出售给亚马逊。对于
a bad return for 12 to 18 months work
12到18个月的工作来说，这笔回报还不错。
but I thought it was much more
但我认为冒险一试更
interesting to take the shot and see
有意思。 看看
what Netflix could become but all of a
Netflix能发展成什么样，但就在
Spring of 2000 we were going to go broke
2000年春季的一两周内，我们突然面临破产。尽管
being successful we tried going to
成功，我们还是尝试了
Blockbuster for months but they weren't
几个月，想把业务拓展到百视达，但他们
going to save us they were going to
救不了我们，反而会
compete with us Netflix wouldn't have
和我们竞争。Netflix本来无法
survived but there's a story which has
生存下去。但有一个故事鲜为人知，
not really been told which took one of
它把
Netflix's biggest impediments and turned
Netflix最大的障碍之一变成了
it into one of its biggest assets so
最大的优势之一。所以，
the DI of AO raffle is about to close
DI of AO的抽奖活动即将结束。
before we hit 7 million subscribers
在我们达到700万订阅用户之前（
which is probably going to be in a
可能就在几天后），任何订阅DI of AO的人都将自动参与
in the raffle and on the day we hit 7
抽奖。在我们达到700万订阅用户当天，
million subscribers we are giving away a
我们将送出
lot of money can't buy prizes to all of
许多千金难买的奖品。
you so hit the Subscribe button get in
所以，点击订阅按钮，在700
before 7 million and I'll announce the
万订阅用户之前加入我们吧！达到700万订阅用户后，我会
prizes and the winners in the comments
在下面的评论区公布奖品和获奖者名单。
[Music]
[音乐]
Mark in this season of your life if you
在你人生的这个阶段，如果你
could consolidate your mission and the
能巩固你的使命和
work that you're doing across the
你正在做的工作，那就太好了。 纵观
content you produce the people you speak
你创作的内容、你接触的人以及
to your professional Endeavors if if you
你的职业努力，如果你
could consolidate that into a singular
能将它们整合为一个单一的、
focused Mission what exactly would that
专注的使命，那么
mission be in this season of your life
在你人生的这个阶段，这个使命究竟是什么？
for me at this point in my life it's all
对我来说，在人生的这个阶段，一切都围绕着
mentorship um you know I've done seven
指导。你知道，我已经创办了七家
startups I kind of recognized quite a
公司，很久以前我就意识到，
while go I do not have uh the appetite
我不再有热情再创办一家了。
24 Focus that I don't want to do anymore
我不想再像以前那样一天24小时都投入到创业中。
I have other things that I would love to
我还有其他想做的事情，
have uh spending time on but you can't
但创业的念头是无法
turn it off uh I've also realized that
停止的。我也意识到，在
over 40 years of being an entrepreneur
过去40多年的创业生涯中，
I've learned a few things about how to
我学到了一些关于如何
actually play this game and so my
玩转这个游戏的经验。所以，我
mission now is how do I pay that forward
现在的使命是如何将这些经验传递下去，
how do I help other people um either
如何帮助其他人，无论是像
have a shot at it like I did or if
我一样尝试创业的人，还是
they're already playing the game how do
已经在创业的人，如何
I try and increase their odds of success
提高他们成功的几率？
you wrote this book called that will
你写了一本书，叫做《那永远不会
never work why books are painful and
奏效：为什么写书很痛苦很
hard to write what is it that you want
艰难》，你希望读完这本书的
someone who gets to the end of this book
人能从中获得什么？ 读完这本书，
to walk away with I've come to believe
我逐渐意识到，
people receive from the General Media
人们从主流媒体那里接收到的
about entrepreneurship is wrong um it
关于创业的信息几乎都是错误的。它
glorifies entrepreneurship in what I
美化了创业，我
think is a damaging way you watch these
认为这是一种有害的方式。你看那些
movies that are about entrepreneurship
关于创业的电影，里面
and it's all about driving around in the
全是开着
fast cars and having the parties and
豪车到处兜风、开派对，但事实并非如此。创业是
that's not it it's a very lonely
一个非常孤独的
profession so in a simple answer the
职业。简单来说，
reason I wrote the book is I wanted to
我写这本书的原因是，我想
give people a true story of what it
给人们讲述一个真实的故事：
really means to come up with a crazy
一个看似疯狂的
idea that everyone thinks is never going
想法，在所有人看来都
to work and the struggle to make it real
行不通，然后如何努力将其变成现实。
and if someone reads that book and gets
如果有人读完这本书后觉得“
to the end and goes this sounds great
这听起来很棒”，那么这个人就是最适合
who should be an entrepreneur if someone
创业的人。如果有人觉得“
goes this sounds a lot harder than I
这比我
expected well then I've done a a service
想象的要难得多”，那么我也算是做了一件好事，因为
in that way as well which is I've kept
我阻止了
someone from getting into this for all
一些人因为
the wrong
错误的
reasons when you when you look back on
原因进入这个行业。当你回顾自己去
Netflix do you you know I remember
Netflix的创业历程时，你会想起
hearing in Steve Jobs speak about the
史蒂夫·乔布斯在
hindsight that in when he reflects on
反思
his life resulted in him starting apple
人生时谈到的那些事后看来至关重要的决定。 最终促使他创办了苹果公司，
and the decisions he made within Apple
以及他在苹果公司内部做出的种种决定。
so obviously you know things he's famous
众所周知，
for saying is that he went to a
他曾旁听过一个字体
typography class he dropped in and he
排印课，并
started learning about design and
开始学习设计和
typography and that shaped him what are
字体排印，这些经历塑造了他。回想起来，
those early sort of experiences that in
这些早期的经历又是如何
hindsight fed into the creation of
促成了
Netflix probably the meta thing was the
Netflix的诞生的呢？或许更重要的是，他早期的尝试
fact that most of these Endeavors were
大多都带有
entrepreneurial so for example initially
创业性质。例如，
my first foray into direct response
我最初涉足直接
marketing was when uh
营销领域，是当我申请管理
that I was working for and so what it
我当时工作的一家乐谱公司的邮购部门时。管理
meant to run the mail order division was
邮购部门意味着
every day you got the mail and if you
每天接收邮件，如果
found someone's asking for a list of
发现有人需要一份
great song books you'd make a copy and
优秀的歌曲集清单，我就复印一份
you'd mail it out and then if an order
寄出去。然后，如果
came in you'd go to the warehouse and
有订单，我就去仓库拣货、
pick pack and ship it and that spoke to
包装、发货。这深深吸引了
me and I began experimenting and said
我，我开始尝试，心想：
okay now what happens if I do two pages
如果我做两页纸，
or do it in color what happens if I mail
或者用彩色印刷，再邮寄
it out and I built this mail order
出去呢？我最终把这个邮购
division into a real mail order company
部门发展成了一家真正的邮购公司。
so it was this combination of direct
所以，这既是直接营销的结合，
response but more importantly it was
更重要的是…… 当时正在
building something it was creating a
打造一些东西，相当于
company inside a company so there are
在一家公司里创建一家公司，所以
certainly those preparations from the
从直接营销的角度来看，这些准备工作
for at least
对至少
Netflix uh because if you think about it
Netflix 来说意义重大。因为如果你仔细想想，
what direct response marketing is about
直接营销的本质
is all about testing it's all about
就是测试，就是
analytics um and when the internet came
分析。当互联网
along and I saw what the internet was
出现，当我看到互联网的本质时，我
what immediately popped into my head was
脑海中立刻浮现出一个想法：天哪，
oh my gosh this would is the power to do
这简直就是
direct marketing but on steroids this is
直接营销的超级版！它更加积极，更加
so much more positive I'm doing this
有效。我做的是
personalization but it's very Brute
个性化，但这是一种非常粗暴的
Force personalization I mean it's it's
个性化。我的意思是，
dear Steven wouldn't your friends at 17
亲爱的史蒂文，你住在新月街 17 号的朋友们，你们不会觉得
Crescent cir it's like this ridiculous
这种
personalization what the internet let me
个性化很荒谬吧？互联网让我可以为
do is personalize every web page for one
每个用户个性化定制每个网页。
person but one of the direct response
但我做过的一个直接营销
Endeavors that I did was I was a
项目是，我曾担任
circulation director for a magazine we
一家杂志的发行总监。
we launched a magazine and that's
我们推出了一本杂志，采用
subscription and so you go okay well
订阅模式。所以你会想，好吧，
look at this you have someone who's
看看，有人在
doing Direct marketing and there's
做直接营销，
someone who's doing subscription and
有人在做订阅，
then all of a sudden they're trying to
然后突然之间，他们都在努力
figure out how to do video rental better
弄清楚如何…… 视频租赁业务发展得更好，
it's not that big of a leap to say okay
说它
it was subscription and it was direct
是订阅模式和
response on the internet so yeah these
互联网直接营销模式之间的过渡并不难，所以这些
things were pretty formative so
经历确实对我影响很大，很
interesting so you on one hand you had
有意思。一方面，你经营着一家
this business where you were physically
实体
sending things in the post and then you
邮寄业务，另一方面，你又
got involved in another business where
涉足
you were doing subscriptions and these
订阅业务。
kind of I guess plant these sort of
我想，这些经历就像在
seeds in your brain to IND industries
你脑海中埋下了种子，让
that you start to understand and it's
你开始理解独立行业。
funny because when people think about
有趣的是，当人们谈到
creativity I heard someone say before
创造力时，我之前听人说过，
that creativity is essentially
创造力本质上是
collecting lots of different clouds and
收集各种不同的灵感，
then connecting them in new new ways so
然后以新的方式将它们连接起来。也就是说，从
inspiration in life and then connecting
生活中获得各种不同的灵感，然后
them in new ways which create a new
以新的方式将它们连接起来，创造出新的
thing and that kind of sounds like what
事物。这听起来很像
you're describing there it is and the
你描述的内容。没错，就是这样。关键在于，当时
thing is at the time you don't
你
necessarily know um you're in the right
未必知道自己是否身处正确的时间和地点，
place at the right time because I
因为我
certainly wasn't the only person who
肯定不是唯一一个
said wow the internet could be a
意识到互联网可以成为
powerful force for selling things uh
强大销售力量的人。杰夫·
Jeff Bezos was
贝佐斯是
one of the first people to recognize the
最早认识到互联网销售潜力的人之一，亚马逊也是如此，当时它只销售
Amazon which at the time was only books
书籍，
but there were a lot of different models
但后来发展出了许多其他业务。 我们本来可以考虑不同的模式，而
of Netflix going into video rental and
Netflix进军视频租赁领域，尤其是通过
doing video rental by mail that was
邮寄方式出租视频，
entirely driven by the fact that I had
完全是因为我曾
worked for so long in a catalog business
在目录公司工作多年，负责
where I had mailed things in boxes and I
邮寄各种包裹，对
had seen I knew a lot about all the
各种
shippers and I knew a lot about
货运公司和
fast shipping I mean I had this huge
快速运输都非常了解。我积累了大量的
repository of of information and
信息和
experience and I didn't know how it be
经验，但我不知道该如何
used but all of a sudden you're looking
运用。突然间，你面对一个
at a problem and you're kind of in your
问题，开始思考
mind going through how could I possibly
如何用
solve this in different ways and one of
不同的方法解决这个问题，其中一个思路就是
you've experienced in the past you
你过去的经历。你在1996到1997年间
launched this company Integrity QA
创办了Integrity QA公司，
ultimately acquired by Reed Hastings by
最终被Reed Hastings的公司收购。是的，你和Reed Hastings就是在那里认识的。
pure by Reed Hastings company yes and
没错，
Netflix what was that like that first
Netflix的另一位联合创始人是谁？你和
meeting with Reed Hastings meeting Reed
Reed Hastings的第一次见面是怎样的？和Reed Hastings的会面就像是
Minds uh we both recognize something in
心灵的交汇，我们彼此都看到了
each other one is that we both approach
对方的某些特质。 首先，我们俩解决
problems very differently I was very
问题的方式截然不同。我当时情绪很
emotional about it I don't mean
激动，我说的激动不是那种哭着跑出
the room I mean empathy that I'm a
房间的程度，而是指同理心。我是个市场
marketing person
营销人员，
uh when I put something out there I can
当我推出产品时，我
almost intuitively sense how someone's
几乎能凭直觉感觉到别人会作何
going to respond Reed his background is
反应。而里德的背景是
mathematics and computer science much
数学和计算机科学，他更注重
more logical much more methodical and we
逻辑，更讲究方法。
kind of realized as we begin solving
当我们开始
problems together how well those two
一起解决问题时，我们逐渐意识到这两种特质是如何完美
integrated but at the same time as
融合的。但与此同时，尽管我们
having these differences and approaches
有着不同的方法和思路，
we were very similar and that we both
我们却有很多相似之处，我们都
shared this commitment to honest y not
秉持着诚实的原则。这并非
because we both swore an oath just was
因为我们都发过誓，而是
our nature that life was too short to
我们的本性使然：人生苦短，不应
shade the truth that if you had
隐瞒真相。如果你有
something to say you say it and you say
什么想说的，就应该说出来，而且要用
it in a respectful way in an empathetic
尊重和同理心的
way and you don't have ulterior motives
方式，不带任何私心。
um and we both were like that and it
我们俩都是这样，这
allowed us to have these really intense
让我们能够进行一些非常深入、非常
interesting conversations where we were
有趣的对话，我们
trying to find the truth out of
试图从中找出真相，
something but pushing each other and
互相激励，
challenging each each other and it ended
互相挑战。最终，这
up being a very very powerful way to
成为了一种非常有效的
solve problems and we were only at pure
解决问题的方式。而我们当时只是在Pure
Atria together for seven or eight months
Atria工作。 我们在一起七八个月后，
again where pure Atria was now being
又一次天灾降临，Pure Atria被
acquired uh and this time um both Reed
收购了。这次，
and I were going to lose our jobs they
我和Reed都要失业了。他们
already had a CEO they already had a
已经有了CEO，也已经有了
senior VP of worldwide marketing so we
全球营销高级副总裁，所以我们都要
were going to be out of a job uh we had
失业了。我们还有
six months and Reed was going to go back
六个月的时间，Reed打算回
to school get a higher degree in
学校攻读
education I was going to start my next
教育学学位，我打算创办自己的下一家
company and Reed wanted to keep a finger
公司，而Reed想继续参与公司的发展。我们达成了
in the pie here and we came to an
一项
agreement that I would start the company
协议：我来创办公司，
uh he would be my angel investor and
他做我的天使投资人，也担任
he'd be my board chair and all we needed
董事会主席。我们需要的仅仅
was the business
是一个商业
idea uh and all you needed was a
想法。没错，我们只需要一个
business idea exactly and only that yeah
商业想法，仅此而已。就这样，
Reed and I kind of searching for a
我和Reed开始了长达数月的寻找
business idea and we we had a
商业想法的过程。我们有一套
methodology so don't uh don't think this
方法论，所以别以为这完全是
random um and Reed and I happened to
偶然。我和Reed碰巧
live in the same town we lived in Santa
住在同一个城市，我们都住在加州
Cruz California together and we had
圣克鲁斯。
gotten in the habit many months earlier
几个月前，我们养成了
of commuting to work together and so
一起上下班的习惯。后来，当
once we knew we were selling the company
我们得知要卖掉公司、
once we were were losing our jobs we
即将失业后，我们
still were commuting to work but now the
仍然一起上下班。但
conversation in the car shifted and what
车里的谈话内容发生了变化。每次都是
would happen is Reed would pick me up at
里德开车来我
my house and we'd barely B my driveway
家接我，车刚开到我家车道，
and I get okay Reed I've got one for you
我就跟他说：“里德，我有个主意，给你推荐
personalized
定制
shampoo you're going to cut off a lock
洗发水。你剪下一缕
of your hair you're going to mail it to
头发寄给
us and we're going to have a team of
我们，我们会安排一个
hair scientists who are going to
头发科学家团队，为你
formulate a custom blend and people are
调制专属配方，然后大家可以
going to subscribe to it
订阅。” 但
matter what I pitched is there'd be
无论我怎么推销，他都
silence re would be staring out the
沉默不语。他
window just steering the car and you'd
只是盯着窗外，专心开车，你以为
think he hadn't even heard me but I knew
他根本没听见我说话。但我知道，在
that kind of behind that stoic face all
那副冷漠的表情背后，他正在暗中
the calculations were taking place like
计算
you know the risk and reward and the
风险、回报、
costs and the benefits and it might take
成本和收益。也许会
five minutes 10 minutes of silence but
沉默五分钟，也许十分钟，但
then eventually he would turn to me and
最终他会转过头来对我说：“这
go that will never work and he would lay
行不通。”然后开始滔滔不绝地讲个不停。 他会跟我列举
into me with all the reasons such a bad
各种理由，说这是个馊
idea but of course I could come prepared
主意，但我当然可以做好准备，带着
the research I had done all the reasons
我做的所有研究成果，以及
I was sure it was a good idea and we
我确信这是个好主意的所有理由，然后我们一路争论
way to the office and if need be all the
到办公室，必要时甚至一路争论
way home and until we either decided
到家，直到我们决定这个主意有
there was promise or no promise and
希望还是没有希望。
almost all of the time there was very
几乎所有时候，
very little promise in these
这些
ideas but next day I'd have another one
想法都没什么希望，但第二天我又会冒出另一个想法，比如
I could read personalized pet food
定制宠物食品、
Uh custom Sporting Goods vitamins I mean
定制运动用品、维生素等等。
I pitched all those
我把这些
ideas I pitched them on video rental by
想法都推销了出去，包括邮寄录像带租赁——
mail people are going to come to the
人们会访问
website they're going to pick out a
网站，选择一部
movie we're going to mail them the movie
电影，我们会把电影邮寄给他们，他们可以
and they'll keep it for a week and then
保留一周，然后
they'll mail it back and at the time
再寄回来。
though this was
不过，在
1996 97 uh video rental you may remember
1996、97年，录像带租赁还是VHS录像带，你可能还记得，它们
too big and too heavy and too expensive
太大、太重、太贵，
and so that idea got trashed the exactly
所以这个想法就像
the same way that the dog food and the
狗粮和
personalized shampoo did and kept on
定制洗发水一样，被否决了。然后我继续
searching and then the Breakthrough if
寻找其他的方案。 然后，突破性的进展——如果真有突破的话——发生在一天
there was one came one morning or Reed
早上，或者说里德来接
picked me up and I'm on my way out the
我，我正要出门，
door out at the driveway I got one for
走到车道上，
you and he stops me and goes I got to
他拦​​住我说：“我得跟
tell you about something I read about
你说说我读到的一件事。
there's this technology that came out
有一种新技术，
it's called the DVD it's this little
叫做DVD，它是一种可以
disc that holds a movie
存储电影的小光盘，又薄又轻。”
and it's thin and it's light and we
我们
brainstormed that a little bit and
稍微讨论了一下，
realized this could be the unlock for
意识到这或许能解决我们
had talked about six or eight weeks ago
六到八周前讨论过的邮寄录像带租赁问题。
and then we did this quintessentially
然后，我们做了件典型的
entrepreneurial thing which is midc
创业事——就像在MIDC
commute we turned the car around and
通勤时那样，我们掉头开回
drove the car back into Santa Cruz to
圣克鲁斯，
try and validate this idea we did not go
想验证一下这个想法。我们没有去
to the office and do a business plan we
办公室写商业计划，也
did not work on a pitch deck we tried to
没有准备路演PPT，而是试图让
collide the idea with real people that
这个想法与真实的人碰撞。
day that day midc commute turned the car
那天，我们掉头开
around went down into Santa Cruz tried
回圣克鲁斯，
to buy a DVD couldn't find one settled
想买一张DVD，但没找到，只好
for buying a used music CD same size
买了一张二手音乐CD，大小和
same weight then went two doors down and
重量都一样。然后，我们又去了两家店外，
bought a little envelope like you'd put
买了一个小信封。 你会放
a greeting card in and put this CD in
一张贺卡，把这张CD放进
the envelope addressed it to Reed's
信封里，写上里德
house bought a stamp and dropped it in
家的地址，买张
the mail and went to work and that very
邮票，然后去上班。
next morning when Reed picked me up he
第二天早上里德来接我的时候，他手里拿着
held up a little pink envelope with an
一个粉红色的小信封，里面装着一张
unbroken CD in it that had got into his
完好无损的CD，
house in less than 24 hours for the
不到24小时就寄到了他家，只花了
price of a stamp and that was probably
一张邮票的钱。大概就是那
the moment we said this actually might
一刻，我们意识到这方法或许真的可行，
work we can use the post office um and
我们可以利用邮局。这
that shifted everything and that's the
改变了一切，也是从那时起，
point we began saying this could be the
我们开始讨论这或许可以成为
idea that we do together so many
我们共同的事业。很多
entrepreneurs and aspiring entrepreneurs
创业者和有抱负的创业者都处于这样一个
are at that exact phase where they want
阶段：他们想要
to leave their corporate job their brain
辞掉现在的工作，他们的大脑现在走到
everywhere they go now because they W
哪儿都想着这件事，因为他们已经
they've wired themselves to be looking
养成了寻找灵感的
for an idea is finding lots of random
习惯，会发现很多随机的
ideas their dog or like throw up and
想法，比如他们的狗吐出来的东西，
they'll be like oh new dog food or
他们就会说“哦，新的狗粮”之类的。
whatever and they're going through that
他们正在经历这个
process and I I think it's so important
过程。我认为，在这个阶段停下来，仔细思考一下判断一个想法是否成功的框架非常重要，
not like how how did you CU presumably
比如，你是如何…… 想必
you had got yourself passionate about
你对
the um shampoo idea so like how do you
洗发水这个想法充满热情，那么你是如何
know when to drop an idea and how do you
判断何时放弃一个想法，
know when to commit to an idea what was
何时坚持一个想法的呢？
the framework you're using the framework
你使用的框架是什么？我的框架
is that every idea is stupid there is
是：每个想法都很蠢。
everyone you know listen you probably
你认识的每个人，听着，你可能
haven't had a corporate job yet in your
还没在公司工作过，
no thank God yes thank God is right
谢天谢地。没错，谢天谢地，
because there's this thing in corporate
因为在公司里，
uh I say Corporate America corporate
呃，我说的是美国公司，
world and it's the brainstorming session
或者说是整个企业界，有一种叫做头脑风暴的环节。
and they put everyone in a conference
他们会把所有人召集到会议
room and they go we're going to
室，然后说：“我们要进行
brainstorm and try to come up with an
头脑风暴，想出一个好
idea for whatever it is and he goes but
点子。” 他会说：“但是
first some ground rules for the
首先，头脑风暴有一些基本规则。”
brainstorming rule number one there is
第一条规则：
no such thing as a bad
没有坏的
idea and I call there's plenty
想法。我对此嗤之以鼻。
of bad ideas in fact there's no such
坏的想法有很多，事实上，根本没有
thing as a good idea every idea is bad
好的想法。每个想法都是坏的，
we just don't know why they're bad yet
我们只是还不知道它们为什么坏。
and so the framework I approach I assume
所以我的框架是：我假设
all these ideas are ridiculous I assume
所有这些想法都很荒谬，我假设
none of them are going to work but
它们都不会奏效。但
here's the difference the reason I start
区别在于，我
from that that uh position is I don't
从这个立场出发的原因是：我并不……
you can do as an entrepreneur which is
创业者最不应该做的一件事就是
fall in love with your
爱上自己的
idea and you talk about the person who
想法。就像有人
sees the dog throwing up and they go
看到狗呕吐，然后说：“
I've got a great idea and then what
我有个好主意！”结果呢？什么
happens nothing they go home and they go
都没发生。他们回家后又觉得“
this is a great idea and they tell their
这真是个好主意”，然后告诉了他们的
partner and their partner goes oh that's
伴侣。伴侣说：“哦，
brilliant I'd buy that
太棒了，我买单！”
and so they go okay and they begin
于是他们开始
working on a business plan and they
着手制定商业计划，
write this 10-page business plan and
写出了长达十页的计划书，满脑子都是“这主意太棒了！”之类的幻想。他们想象着这想法会
They're how amazing it's going to be
多么惊艳，比如“
just think about we have this line of we
我们还
can do cats too and then giraffes you
可以做猫咪，还有长颈鹿！”等等。他们
incredibly ornate business in their head
脑子里构建了一个无比精妙的商业蓝图，而这一切都
all based on this feeling that this must
基于“这肯定
be a good idea and you've got to nip
是个好主意”的错觉。你必须扼杀这种幻想。
that in the bud and the way you nip it
扼杀它的方法是：与其沉浸在幻想中，
in the bud is you try rather than
不如
first thing you think about the only
先思考
thing you think about is how can I
如何
quickly cheaply and easily Collide this
快速、低成本、轻松地将这个
idea with a real person and find out is
想法付诸实践，看看
it in fact a good idea or a bad idea how
它是否真的可行。 想法，或者说坏想法，
can I do some kind of hack that will
我该如何
allow me to quickly find out whether
快速地找到某种方法，来验证
customers actually would want this or
客户是否真的需要它？
not and almost always you build this
几乎总是要
quick cheap down and dirty I don't mean
快速、廉价、简陋地搭建一个简易的测试工具。我
minimal viable product I mean
说的不是最小可行产品（MVP），而是
unviable something you can quickly do
不可行的方案。你可以快速地尝试一下，
like turn the car around and mail a CD
比如掉头给自己寄一张CD，
to yourself just to find out the the
看看是否真的
basic premise of can I actually use the
能用
US mail to send movies back and forth
美国邮政来回寄送电影。
because if that had failed well great on
如果失败了，那就继续下
to the next one and that's such a
一个。这是
critical critical step that's the
至关重要的一步，是
framework that everyone has to to have
每个人都必须掌握的框架。关键
it is not about having a good idea
不在于拥有一个好想法，
having ideas is easy and trivial the
拥有想法很容易，也很简单。
important thing is how clever can you be
重要的是你如何巧妙地
to come up with a quick and cheap and
想出一个快速、廉价、
easy way to test it why because I know
简便的测试方法。为什么呢？因为我知道
you and me understand this but I didn't
你我都明白这一点，但
understand this when I started my career
我刚入行的时候并不明白。
so I know that there's a lot of people
我知道
listening right now that are probably
现在有很多听众可能正处于
right in the moment you've described
你描述的那种状态：
they've spent a year building up this
他们在卧室里花了一年时间搭建这个
thing in their bedroom for anyone that
东西（如果有人
can't see he's got his head in his hands
看不到，他正双手抱头）。
um they' spent a year in their bedroom
他们花了一年时间…… 在他们的卧室里
building and working on this project why
建造这个项目，为什么这是一个
is that a terrible idea it's such a
糟糕的主意？这简直是
waste of time because what happens is
浪费时间。因为会
two things happen one is this or idea
发生两件事：一是这个想法
complicated in your head that you go
在你的脑海里变得如此庞大、复杂和繁复，以至于你会想：
okay Mark I need to get started I need
好吧，马克，我得开始了，我需要
to raise $5 million because it's going
筹集500万美元，因为要
to have to hire all these people to to
雇佣很多人来
build this thing and they're probably
建造这个项目，而他们很可能
building the absolutely the wrong thing
建造的完全是错误的东西。
uh you you can't you you can't just go
你不能，你不能仅仅
ahead and based on what you think is
根据你认为将会
going to happen you've got to start from
发生什么就贸然行动，你必须从掌握
a position of real information listen
真实信息的基础上开始。听着，
perhaps the cleanest way since we have a
也许最简洁的方法是，既然我们还
bit of time is to give you an example I
有些时间，就举个例子吧。我经常
do a lot of work with University
和
students and uh I was meeting with a
大学生一起工作，我遇到了一位
young woman who uh at the University and
大学里的年轻女性，
she goes okay Mark I've got this idea um
她说：好吧，马克，我有个想法，
what I want to do is peer-to-peer
我想做的是点对点的
clothing sharing in other words I've got
服装共享。换句话说，
all this clothing in my closet that I
我的衣柜里有很多衣服，我
never wear or I don't wear very often
从来不穿或者很少穿，
and I know my friends have a lot of
我知道我的朋友们
clothing in their closet and other
衣柜里也有很多衣服，其他
friends have clothes in their closet it'
朋友也有很多衣服。  c 她们衣柜里的衣服，
be great if we had this website and we
要是能有个网站就好了，
could all post what we have and we could
大家都可以把自己
borrow each other's clothes and and I'm
的衣服发上来，互相借穿。我说，
going okay that's interesting what can I
好啊，这主意不错，有什么可以
help you with she goes I'm trying to
帮你的吗？她说，我正在考虑要不要为了
to do this uh how do I raise the money
做这个网站而辍学，呃，我该怎么筹钱
to hire a team to build this for me and
雇个团队帮我建这个网站呢？
I went whoa you know slow down here okay
我说，哇，你先别急。好吧，
interesting idea but let's figure out if
想法不错，但我们得想想能不能
we can come up with a quick and cheap
找到一个快速、便宜
and easy way to collide this idea with
又简单的办法，把这个想法变成
the reality I said do you have a piece
现实。我说，你有
of paper she goes yes smartass I'm a
纸吗？她说，有啊，你个自作聪明的家伙，我是个
college student I have a piece of paper
大学生，我有纸。我说，太好了，那
I go great all right do you have a magic
你有
a marker she goes I have a marker do you
记号笔吗？她说，我有
have a piece of tape she goes got a
记号笔。那你有胶带吗？她说，我有胶带。我说，
piece of tape I go all right I want you
好的，我想让你
to write on the piece of paper would you
在纸上写上“你
like to borrow my clothes
想借我的衣服吗？”，
knock and I want you to tape that to the
然后把纸贴到
outside of your dormatory room and we're
你宿舍外面。
going to find out in the next 24 hours
接下来的24小时，我们就能知道
behind your idea is real is anyone going
你这个想法背后的第一个原则是否成立了。 真的会有人
to knock because if nobody knocks well
敲门吗？如果没人敲门，那
you've learned something very important
你就学到了非常重要的一点。
right there this thing you think is so
你觉得很
attractive might not be but let's let's
吸引人的东西可能并非如此。但我们
be optimistic let's assume a bunch of
乐观一点，假设很多
people knock great you've learned
人来敲门，太好了，你学到了
something but you're also going to learn
一些东西。但你还会学到
the next thing which is are there
下一件事：衣服合身吗？
with style are the people who knock and
款式有问题吗？那些敲门
look at your clothes actually going to
看你衣服的人真的会
want any of them all right let's be even
想要吗？好吧，我们再
more optimistic let's say they do find
乐观一点，假设他们真的找到了
out ones they want to borrow well you're
想借的衣服。那么你
going to find out the next piece how do
接下来会发现，当
you feel when your favorite blouse comes
你最喜欢的衬衫被
back stained or torn you're going to
弄脏或撕破后，你会是什么感受？你会
find out about the cost of doing dry
知道干洗的费用，
cleaning you're going to find out all of
你会知道所有
these things and you're going to find
这些问题。而这一切，你只需要
about all this for a piece with a piece
一张纸、一卷
of paper a tape and a marker none of
胶带和一支记号笔就能搞定。不用
this raising money dropping at a school
筹款，不用去学校，
and doing any coding you're going to do
也不用写代码。你只需要做一件
something very simple now is this
非常简单的事情。这种方法可扩展吗？不可扩展。这种方法可
scalable no is this repeatable no but
重复吗？不可重复。但这
that's fine you're going to do it all
没关系，你只需要
with 3x5 cards or on a pad you're going
3x5英寸的卡片就能完成所有工作。 或者在平板电脑上
to do it manually and you're going to
手动操作，你会
start losing your mind but when you
开始抓狂，但当你
finally get to the point where you are
最终准备好，
ready to go and maybe raise money or
可能要筹集资金或
drop out of school you're going to know
辍学时，你会知道
what you're dropping at a school for
你为什么辍学，
you're going to know what you're raising
你会知道你为什么筹集
money for you're going to be able to
资金，你会能够
tell someone here's my acquisition cost
告诉别人：这是我的获客成本，这是
here's my lifetime value here's my CAC
我的终身价值，这是我的获客成本，
here's my you're going to know all of
这是我的……你会了解所有
these metrics you're going to know the
这些指标，你会了解
complexity you're going to a tried all
复杂性，你会尝试所有
these different things you're going to
不同的方法，你会了解目标受众，
know what demographic and you found out
而你发现这一切，
all of that for nothing except for your
除了
time that's what I mean by figure out
时间之外，没有任何其他成本。这就是我所说的，找到
some way to validation hack and that is
某种验证方法，这是
the key to being an entrepreneur you
成为企业家的关键。你
have an idea quickly cheap and easy test
有一个想法，快速、廉价、轻松地测试
it find out it's ridiculous abandon it
它，发现它很荒谬，放弃它，
go on to the next one it's funny because
继续下一个。有趣的是，
uh obviously I'm a dragon on Dragon Den
显然我是《龙穴》（Dragon Den）的“龙”，这
which is basically a show like Shark
基本上是一个类似《创智赢家》（Shark
Tank where we see 100 pitches a year
Tank）的节目，我们每年都会看到100个企业家的项目路演，
from entrepreneurs and what I observe in
而我…… 观察
some of those pitches especially when
一些商业计划，尤其是在
they're a little bit early on and they
早期阶段，
haven't got product Market fit quite yet
产品尚未完全与市场契合，也
there hasn't been evidence that the
没有证据表明
market actually cares is a huge amount
市场真正需要它的时候，你会发现其中存在着巨大的
of delusion to the point that you could
错觉。即使你
give someone some feedback but because
给他们一些反馈，他们也往往因为
they've spent one two years of their
投入了一两年的时间，甚至
life and maybe mortgaged their house and
可能抵押了房子，而陷入了
business they're they're now in the sunk
沉没
cost fallacy which is that sort of
成本谬误。这是一种
cognitive bias where you've invested so
认知偏差，指你在某件事上投入了太多，以至于不惜
Defending Your bad decision at all cost
一切代价维护自己的错误决定，
and you can't see the light of day and
看不到任何希望。
um and that you know my first business
你知道，我的第一个创业项目最终以
was the death of my first business but
失败告终，但
for many entrepreneurs that I meet it's
对于我遇到的许多创业者来说，这显然是
quite clearly the death of them because
他们创业失败的根源。因为
if they don't have that humility if
如果他们
they've got romantic they can't take any
缺乏谦逊，过于理想化，就无法接受任何
feedback which is a con conflict with
反馈，这与
what they want to believe it's it's
他们想要相信的相冲突。
you're Stephen you're absolutely right
斯蒂芬，你说得完全正确，
it is the single biggest reason that
这正是他们要么因为过于理想化而放弃创业的最大原因。
it's so big and complex that to get
它如此庞大而复杂，以至于
started is almost impossible or they are
几乎不可能起步，或者他们已经
so far along they can't stop it's it's
走得太远，无法停止。这在
tragic in in a lot of ways that which is
很多方面都是悲剧。这就是
why you have to start from the belief
为什么你必须从相信
that your idea is a bad one uh because
你的想法是糟糕的开始，因为
that makes it easier to walk away from
这样当
it as soon as you realize you are right
你意识到自己是对的时候，就更容易放弃它。
um but what happens if you can get this
但是，如果你能养成这种将
discipline of taking your idea and
想法付诸实践的自律精神，
immediately trying it is almost always
几乎总能
takes you in a New Direction yes your
带你走向新的方向。是的，你
original idea was terrible but oh my
最初的想法很糟糕，但是
gosh did you see how this person did
天哪，你看到这个人是怎么做的吗？我们试试这个，哦，这个行不通，我们
let's try this and that is
试试这个。这就是
entrepreneurship it is just leaping from
创业精神，就像从
the back of one uh alligator to the next
一只鳄鱼的背上跳到另一只鳄鱼的背上，而
and there those alligators just H long
这些鳄鱼只是在你
enough to before they sink or before
被咬之前或被你咬之前停留足够长的时间，然后
they bite you and you jump to the next
你跳到下一只鳄鱼身上。
one I I I think I found two sort of
我认为我发现了两种
species of entrepreneur and the real
类型的创业者，
distinction between them is how long
它们之间的真正区别在于他们从事创业的时间长短。
entrepreneur that I know they care
我知道有一种创业者完全在乎
their initial hypothesis being correct
他们的最初假设是否正确，
and that's typically the young
那就是…… 通常来说，年轻的
entrepreneur and then the the more
创业者和经验
seasoned entrepreneur cares entire
丰富的创业者都只关心
about being successful regardless of
成功，无论最终结果是否符合
whether it's via their initial
最初的
hypothesis or not they care entirely
假设。他们只关心
about like saving time and being
节省时间，追求
successful not being right and I think
成功，而不是结果是否正确。我觉得很
it's interesting that tenure as an
有意思的是，
entrepreneur seems to determine which
创业的资历似乎决定了
Camp you sit in it's also your
你属于哪个阵营，当然你的
personality jumping back to our
性格也很重要。回到我们
conversation earlier about What
之前的对话，我和
attracted Reed and I to each other was
里德互相吸引的原因在于，
that both of us were in that camp that
我们都属于那种
said we don't care whose idea it was we
不在乎是谁的想法，
just care about getting to the right
只在乎找到正确
answer and part of this culture that we
答案的阵营。我们
had with each other and we built with
彼此之间以及与
other people was you could argue like
其他人共同建立的这种文化的一部分是，你可以像
cats and dogs and eventually you'll
猫狗一样争论不休，最终你会
arrive at what you think is the right
找到你认为正确的方向。
way to go and as soon as that happens
一旦找到正确的方向，
you all fall in behind and no one says I
大家都会团结一致，没有人会说“我
was right I was wrong and you don't even
是对的，我是错的”，你甚至不会
remember who was right and who was wrong
记得谁对谁错。
it's a big piece August 29 1997 Netflix
这很重要。1997年8月29日，你和
was founded by yourself in Reed
里德·
Hastings from from that day onwards did
哈斯廷斯创立了Netflix。从那天起，
did you know at the moment that Netflix
你是否预料到Netflix
was going to ever become what it went on
会发展成后来的规模？
to be what were you thinking it was
你当时以为会是什么样子？
be I am completely astounded and amazed
我对Netflix的发展方向感到无比震惊和惊讶。
never in a million years could I have
我
dreamed of the company that exists now
做梦都想不到，如今的公司会和
about in in August of 1997 it's
1997年8月我们设想的完全一样。这一切
astounding to me what's happened U and
对我来说太不可思议了。
it's the nature of Entrepreneurship you
这就是创业的本质，你
can't predict where these things are
无法预测事情会如何
going to go uh that wasn't the point
发展。不过，这并不是重点。
though it wasn't like Reed and I were in
我和里德当时并没有坐在
the car going uh okay when do we enter
车里讨论“我们什么时候加入
the streaming war and when how do we
流媒体大战？我们什么时候才能
deal with ch no this was a very very
应对……”。不，这是一个非常
simple straightforward problem a video
简单直接的问题。
rental in the United States is8 billion
在美国，视频租赁市场
a year um it's very unpleasant that the
每年高达80亿美元。令人非常不快的是，占据
of that market is doing things which
市场最大份额的公司却在做一些
customers hate there has to be
顾客讨厌的事情。必须有像
Blockbuster there has to be a better way
百视达那样的公司，必须有更好的方法。
that's where it starts from that's the
这就是
problem you're trying to solve and
问题的起点，也是你试图解决的问题。而
trying to solve the problem is this dual
解决这个问题包含两个
thing which is how do you do something
方面：如何做一件事……
that a customer might want solve the
客户可能希望解决
problem for the customer but also how do
问题，但你也需要考虑如何
you make a business out of that and
从中创造商机，而
that's all
这才是真正
consuming uh I remember we had a company
耗费精力的地方。我记得公司成立
meeting early on maybe were two or three
初期，大概两三个月的时候，我们开过一次会议。
months in and I remember getting up in
我记得当时我站在
front of the uh company and laying out
公司前面，提出了一个
what I thought was going to be this big
我认为非常宏大、
hairy audacious goal for us someday
雄心勃勃的目标：有朝一日，我们要
we're going to be one of the top 10
成为
largest video chains in the United
美国十大视频连锁店之一。现在回想起来，这目标简直
ridiculously trivial but from where we
微不足道。但就当时的情况而言，
stood then it may as well have been
这就像
saying we're going to ride our bicycles
说我们要骑自行车
up Mount Everest uh what
登上珠穆朗玛峰一样。真是
hubris uh because even the 10th largest
狂妄自大！因为即使是排名第十的
chain was many many many millions of
连锁店，
dollars a year bigger than we were at
年营业额也比我们当时高出数百万美元。
the time but something to aim for and we
但这毕竟是一个目标。而且我们
actually passed that one way faster than
实际上比预想的更快地实现了这个目标。
we thought and then you set your goal
然后你设定了你的目标，
you know eventually we're going to be as
你知道，最终我们要达到
Blockbuster in other
百视达（Blockbuster）的规模。
words if you were to set your goals to
换句话说，如果你把目标设定为
be what Netflix is now I would be
成为现在的Netflix那样，那我早就被
locked up I would have been this most
关起来了，那
ridiculous flight of fancy hallucination
简直就是天方夜谭。
you can imagine they would have thought
你可以想象，
if you had ever done a presentation
如果你曾经做过一个演讲，
saying Netflix would be as big as it is
说Netflix会发展到今天这样的规模，他们肯定会觉得你疯了或者像个疯子。
now you um for people that don't know
嗯，对于那些不了解情况的人来说，
because the world has moved on so much
因为世界变化太快了，
are listening to this conversation right
现在正在听我们谈话的一代人
now that probably don't even know what a
可能甚至不知道
like a vcr and a cassette player is but
录像机和卡带播放机是什么。但
you launched the business at a time when
你创办这家公司的时候，
Blockbuster was the big incumbent and
百视达（Blockbuster）还是行业巨头。百视达是
Blockbuster was was a store where you
一家实体店，你得去店里
went to a physical location you rented a
租一台
like cassette VCR what do they call it
录像机，就是那种卡带播放
like a VCR v VHS VHS tape you took it
机，VHS录像带，你把它带
home and then you brought it back the
回家，
next day and your real Innovation was
第二天再还回去。你真正的创新在于，
that you were going to send these DVDs
你要把这些DVD
to people in the post on a rental
以租赁的方式邮寄给顾客。
basis that was the that was the Crux of
这才是
the business right that was the Crux of
业务的核心，对吧？这才是
the business and in fact when we
业务的核心。事实上，我们
originally started there was not a lot
最初创业的时候，
of business model Innovation there
商业模式也没有什么创新，
either you know there was due dates and
你知道，有到期日，还有
there was late fees the Innovation was
滞纳金。创新之处在于，我们建立了
it was one centralized store on the
一个集中式的
internet that served the entire country
互联网商店。 我们服务于全国，
so that we could have every single movie
所以我们拥有所有DVD电影，
inventory uh and unlike a video rental
库存完美。与录像带租赁店不同，录像带租赁
store where you can picture it in like a
店就像
supermarket with rows of shelves each
超市一样，货架一排排，每部
movie could be placed in one place you
电影只能放在一个地方，
could either put it in the mystery aisle
比如神秘区、
or in the Alfred Hitchcock aisle
希区柯克区
or in the new Rel you had to pick where
或者新片区，你必须自己选择放在哪里。
it was whereas on the internet you could
而在互联网上，
have that same movie listed in 30
同一部电影可能会出现在30个
different places based on finding movies
不同的地方。
we thought finding movies would be
我们当时认为，在网上查找电影也会更
easier too we had a bunch of things we
容易。我们有很多想法，
in hindsight when I think about a lot of
认为
these big breakthrough ideas that ended
这些想法能让我们挑战这家庞大的行业巨头。但确实，我们的业务非常专注，没有流媒体服务。如果你想看电影，我们会把光盘邮寄给你。现在回想起来，很多最终改变行业的重大突破性想法背后都有
learn in hindsight that there was some
一些
big macro factors that caused the timing
宏观因素，促成了时机的
to be right and I think about in the
成熟。就
case of your business Netflix there's a
Netflix而言，也有很多
bunch of big macro things that you've
宏观因素。 您
already described things like DVDs the
已经提到了DVD和
internet is there is there any other
互联网，那么还有其他什么
sort of big macro factors that made the
宏观因素促成了
timing right for Netflix those were the
Netflix的诞生吗？这
two big ones right is that the internet
两个因素确实很重要。互联网
was certainly the big one was that all
无疑是最重要的因素，它让
of a sudden there was this way to have a
一家实体
single store which served the entire
店就能服务
country before for a bricks and mortar
全国。以前，实体店
as we call it business you want to serve
要想服务
the entire country you've got to build
全国，就得开
9,000 different stores and Blockbuster
9000家分店，而百视达（Blockbuster）就是这么做的，
did just that they had 9,000 different
他们有9000家
stores and then you have to staff those
分店，还要配备员工，
stores and they had 60,000
他们有6万名
employees and we served the entire
员工。而我们只用
country with one inventory and with a
一套库存和
group of 12 to 15 people so that was
12到15人的团队就服务了全国。这
certainly one big shift uh the DVD was a
无疑是一个巨大的转变。至于DVD，当时DVD
bet which was at the time DVD was just
刚刚
getting started and if the DVD had not
起步，如果DVD没能
worked if it had not reached a full
成功，没能普及到千家万户，Netflix就
never would have worked how many people
不可能成功。Netflix
launched Netflix there was fewer than
上线时，DVD播放
200 50,000 DVD players sold that was the
机的销量不到20万台，总共也就卖了5万台。
total addressable Market was
潜在市场只有
250,000 DVD players so is that like 1%
25万台DVD播放机，这大概占
of America or something yeah there's 130
美国人口的1%吧？美国有1.3
million households in the United States
亿户家庭，
so and of those 130 million households
而在这1.3亿户家庭中，
movie uh but it was Tiny there it was
电影市场规模很小。这
really it created all kinds of
确实带来了各种
interesting marketing challenges of how
有趣的营销挑战，比如如何在潜在
few eligible customers in September 99
客户如此稀少的情况下推出一家公司。1999年9月，
you explored selling Netflix to Amazon
你们曾考虑将Netflix出售给亚马逊，这距离
you'd launched
你们成立还不到两年。
um what was was that the first time you
嗯，那是你第一次
met Jeff Bezos yes and how does that
见到杰夫·贝佐斯吗？是的，那是怎么发生的呢？
come to be you know because he's he at
因为当时他……
the time I guess was was fairly early in
我想，当时亚马逊的创业历程也还很早期。是的，当时……为了
and at the time to show you how early
说明
Amazon was in its Journey they were only
亚马逊的创业历程有多早期，他们当时只是
they were a bookstore but Jeff had made
一家书店，什么都不卖。但杰夫
no secret of the fact that his
毫不掩饰他的
aspirations went way beyond that that he
雄心壮志，他要
was going to be the everything store
成为一家包罗万象的商店，
that the things they had found about how
他们发现
powerful it was selling books in the
互联网上销售书籍的强大力量可以
internet applied to everything else and
应用到其他所有领域，而且
it was pretty clear his next two
非常…… 明确了接下来的两个
categories we're going to be music and
类别，我们将是音乐和
movies and we got a call from uh the CFO
电影。我们接到了亚马逊首席财务官的电话，他
at Amazon basically saying hey Jeff we'd
基本上是这么说的：嘿，杰夫，我们
love to uh meet with you how about
很想见见你，要不要来
coming on up to up to Seattle and having
西雅图坐坐，
a little sit down and Reed and I didn't
坐下来聊聊？我和里德很快就
need to think too long to understand why
明白了
they might want to meet with us uh it
他们为什么想见我们。
was pretty clear they were going to be
很明显，他们要
entering video and this was going to be
进军视频领域，而这次会面将
a make versus buy analysis would buying
分析自建还是收购，看看收购
Netflix accelerate their entry into
Netflix是否会加速他们进军
video cuz we had done a tremendous
视频领域。因为我们在
content and making those things work so
内容开发和运营方面做了大量工作，所以这其中蕴含着
there was some value there not to
一定的价值，
mention the people um and so we all flew
更不用说我们的人才了。于是，我们都飞到了
up to Amazon and were ushered into this
亚马逊，被领进了一栋
building which was pretty hard to
大楼。很难
imagine that this was the headquarters
想象这里竟然是
of this world changing e-commerce
这家改变世界的电商
company because it was a mess you know
公司的总部，因为里面乱糟糟的。你知道，
people were jammed in under stairs and
人们挤在楼梯下、
in closets and there was pizza boxes
壁橱里，到处都是披萨盒，
every place and dogs running around and
狗在周围乱窜。所有的
the desks were all the same they were
桌子都一样，
all made from doors that had been laid
都是用门板做的，
supported by four wooden posts at Each
每个角落都用四根木柱支撑着，
corner that everyone sat at these doors
每个人都坐在那里。 这些门开了，
and uh and in comes Jeff Bezos and we
然后杰夫·贝佐斯走了进来，我们
begin to have this conversation about
开始讨论
what is Netflix and what's it all about
Netflix是什么，它的意义何在。讨论进行得
and uh it went went pretty well
相当顺利。
at the end of the meeting um she Saidi
会议结束时，首席财务官送我们出门，她说：“我
just want to set your
想让你们了解一下，如果
expectations that in the event we decide
我们决定
to do something our offer is probably
出售，我们的报价可能在几千万美元左右。”
figures and and we guessed that was
我们当时估计
probably going to be1 to15
大概是100万到1500万美元。
million and at the time we had launched
当时Netflix是1998年
in April of
4月推出的，
98 and so
所以
we were still pretty young and I
我们还很年轻。我
remember Reed and I kind of looking at
记得我和里德互相看了一眼，心想：
return for 12 to 18 months
对于12到18个月的
work but at the same time we felt we had
工作来说，这回报还不错。但与此同时，我们觉得我们
already solved the big problems we had
已经解决了主要问题：我们
built a functioning e-commerce website
建立了一个功能完善的电子商务网站；
we had managed to Source every single
我们设法找到了所有能
DVD that was available we had figured
找到的DVD；我们
out how to make movies go out to
找到了如何将电影送到
customers and bring them back and we
客户手中以及如何回收电影的方法。我们
weren't quite ready to let Jeff Bezos
还没准备好让杰夫·贝佐斯
take over and so in some ways it was
接管。所以在某种程度上，这与其说是
less about us going up and deciding
我们决定
whether to sell or not it really ended
是否出售，不如说是…… 最后感觉就像是
up being kind of like a commitment
一场承诺
ceremony where Reed and I looked at each
仪式，我和里德互相看着
other in the eyes and said we can get
对方的眼睛，说
out if we want and I think both of us
如果我们想退出可以随时退出，但我认为我们俩都
decided no let's uh let's go for this
决定不退出，让我们放手一搏吧。如果当时有这笔
would that money have changed your life
钱，会改变你的人生吗？
point 1999 you know $400
1999年，你知道，4
million that's a hard to say it this is
亿美元，这很难说出口。
not like I was uh you know living in a
我当时可不是住在
trailer uh and deeply in debt and you
拖车里，也不是负债累累。你
know I I'd been working I was in my late
知道，我已经工作了，快
30s I'd been working in Silicon Valley
40岁了，在硅谷工作了
for a while and I'd had a number of
一段时间，也创办过好几家公司，
startups you know I had G through IPOs
你知道，我
before um so I I had I was comfortable
之前也让一些公司上市过。所以，我当时的生活还算不错。别误会，
don't get me wrong this would have been
这笔钱当然
nice but I'm not sure this would have
很好，但我不确定它会从根本上
dramatically changed my life in some
改变我的人生。
profound way I thought it was much more
我觉得
interesting to take the shot and see
抓住机会，看看
what Netflix could become than to walk
Netflix能发展成什么样，比放弃更有意思。
away what was Jeff like what you
你还
remember in
记得
1999 uh extremely unpolished really if
1999年的杰夫吗？他当时非常不成熟。如果
you see him now I mean he's really buff
你现在看到他，我的意思是，他身材很棒。
and he's really thoughtful and someone
他真的很体贴，而且
has definitely worked on his laugh it's
他的笑声肯定经过了改造，
it's now very
现在很
controlled uh back then it was this
克制。嗯，以前他的笑声就像
almost hysterical hyena like bark and
鬣狗一样歇斯底里地吠叫，
you could hear it from all over the
整栋楼都能听到。
building I'm not going to try and
我可不想
imitate it um but he was tremendously
模仿他那样。嗯，他当时热情爆棚，
enthusiastic like this bundle of energy
就像个精力旺盛的小家伙。
and I remember that um the two of us
我记得我们俩当时一直在讨论
this early startup stuff uh and one
创业初期的各种事情。
thing I remember we had in common is
我记得我们有一个共同点，就是
that um uh at our launch we had rigged
在公司成立之初，我们装了
up a bell to ring every time an order
个铃铛，每次有订单
came in and I was telling him that he
进来就响。我告诉他这件事，他说：“啊，
was going ah we too we had a bell that
我们也有铃铛，
was ringing and we had we shared those
我们分享了这些。”
things and then we were also talking
然后我们还聊到了公司
about names and Netflix had started out
名字。Netflix 最初的
with a strange name which was kibble
名字很奇怪，叫 kibble
kibble and he was saying oh yeah we
kibble。他说：“哦，对，我们
originally were called
最初叫
Kadabra which he meant to sound like
Kadabra，他想让它听起来像
Abracadabra like magic but their lawyer
Abracadabra，像魔法一样。”但是他们的律师
said that Kadabra sounds a little bit
说 Kadabra 听起来太
too much like kadaver and so therefore
像 kadaver 了，所以
Amazon but in other words it was this
亚马逊就用了这个名字。 换句话说，
really interesting us going back and
我们来回讨论真的很有意思，
forth and I know Reed was very impatient
我知道里德很不耐烦，
he just kind of wanted to get down to
他只想赶紧进入
business so finally I go okay Reed Reed
正题，所以我最后说：“好了，里德，里德，
let's talk to the what we're really
咱们
talking about here enough enough startup
谈谈正事吧。够了，够了，创业
is the next big milestone in the Netflix
是Netflix发展历程中的下一个重要里程碑，
crash for you
对你来说，互联网泡沫破裂是……
uh because there's a there's a problem
因为在此
happened um before
之前，可能还有更深刻的时刻，那就是
Netflix uh and that was because the do
Netflix的领导层更迭。这是因为互联网泡沫
crash was in the spring of
破裂发生在
2000 and this was probably in late
2000年春季，而这次（指Netflix的领导层更迭）大概是在
um and Netflix was still young uh and as
Netflix还很年轻。正如
I mentioned at the beginning the
我一开始提到的，我
arrangement that Reed and I had was that
和里德的约定是，
he'd be the angel investor he'd be the
他担任天使投资人，担任
chair uh I'd be the CEO I'd start and
董事长，我担任首席执行官，负责公司的创立和
run the company um and I did that and
运营。我做到了，而
Reed had a day job somewhere
里德在别处还有一份工作。
else um and one afternoon uh late that
那年晚些时候的一个下午，
year Reed poke his Pok his head in my
里德把头探进了我的
office uh late afternoon and said Mark
办公室。” 那天下午晚些时候，马克说
we have to
我们得
talk uh and as you probably can imagine
谈谈。你大概也能猜到，
that never bodess well when someone says
当有人说“
we have to talk and it was right and he
我们得谈谈”的时候，通常都不是什么好兆头。果然不出所料，他
came in and he had a PowerPoint
进来后带着一个PPT，
slideshow and he sat across my desk and
坐在我的办公桌对面，
spun his computer around and began
转动电脑，开始给
walking me through a slideshow about how
我讲解
he felt that I was doing as
他觉得我作为
CEO strengths but perhaps a little bit
CEO的优势，但缺点可能有点
disproportionately
过多。
weaknesses and I was a little taken back
我当时有点懵，就
by this and I I I kind of stopped him
打断了他，说：“我
I am not going to sit here and let you
不会坐在这里让你给
pitch me on how much I
我讲我有多糟糕。”
suck um and I think he was taken back by
我想他也有点懵，
that as well and so he closed the
于是他关掉了
computer but then proceeded to lay out
电脑，然后继续说，
that he was
他
concerned that he had seen minor errors
担心我判断上的一些小错误，
in my judgment that he questioned some
质疑我的一些人事
of the hires I had made I mean he had
任命。当然，他也
seen a lot of the other things i' had
看到了我做的其他一些好事，
done that were good but his point was
但他的重点是，
that we have to execute lawlessly and
我们必须不顾一切地执行，
we're at a point now where things are
现在事情
beginning to accelerate and if there's
开始加速发展，如果
smoke at this level he was worried there
在这个层面上出现任何风吹草动，他担心
was going to be fire later on and uh
以后会出大问题。
eventually he got to his point which is
最后他终于说到重点了，那就是
that uh he wanted to come back to the
他想
company fulltime and be
全职回到公司担任
CEO and for a moment I thought he was
CEO。我当时以为他要
firing me uh CU Reed had more Equity
解雇我，因为CU Reed的股权比
than I did since he was the uh uh
我多，毕竟他是
original
最初的
investor and but as I understood what he
投资人。但我后来明白，他的
was proposing it wasn't that he was
提议并不是他
proposing that he come in as CEO that I
来当CEO，我继续做
stay as coo and that we essentially run
COO，我们俩一起管理
the company
公司。
together and I remember as he finally he
我记得他最后
left the office and he quietly closed
离开办公室，轻轻地
the door and I was so shocked that even
关上门，我当时震惊得说不出话来，
though the sun was going down I sat
尽管太阳已经落山，我仍然呆坐在
there in the dark like without the
黑暗中。 就像失去了所有
strength to the lights on and just kind
力量，连灯都打不亮，整个人都
of crushed and all I could think at the
崩溃了。当时我脑子里只有一个念头：
time was this is so unfair this is my
这太不公平了！这是我的
company you know I started this it was
公司，是我创立的，是
my idea I hired the people I got us
我的想法，是我招的人才，是我让公司运转起来的，
going and how dare you you know all of a
你们怎么敢
sudden take this from
突然把它从
me but as I thought more about it I kind
我手里夺走？但当我仔细思考后，我
of realized that there was another
意识到这里面还有另一种
Dynamic at work
因素在起作用。就像
here and like most
大多数
entrepreneurs when we started Netflix I
创业者一样，在创办Netflix之初，我
had this dream of being a successful CEO
梦想成为
of this big successful
一家成功大
company and I think as I sat there I
公司的CEO。我想，当我坐在那里的时候，我
began to realize that maybe this wasn't
开始意识到，这或许不是
one dream maybe this was two different
一个梦想，而是两个不同的梦想。
successful company might be a different
成功大公司的梦想可能和
dream than the one of me being CEO and I
我成为CEO的梦想是不同的。我
had to really say to myself does Reed
必须认真地问自己：Reed
coming in full-time as CEO increase our
全职加入公司担任CEO，是否真的能增加我们实现这个梦想的
chances of that happening and it was
几率？我很难
really hard for me to argue with myself
说服自己不这么做。
otherwise and I'm not saying this was an
我并不是说这是一个
easy decision and I you know I went home
容易的决定。那天晚上我回到家，
with my wife and we finished a bottle of
和妻子坐在门廊上，喝完了一
wine and I think by the time I went to
瓶酒。我想，到了
bed that night I kind of concluded that
晚上睡觉的时候，我已经基本得出结论：
he was right that if we really wanted to
他是对的。 如果我们真的
give ourselves the best chances of being
想让自己有最大的
successful that I should move over
成功机会，我就应该让位，
I should step down as CEO and let Reed
卸任CEO，让里德
come in as CEO and we should run the uh
接任，我们
together
一起管理公司。
and looking back now this was 20 some
现在回想起来，那是二十
odd years
多年前的事了，当时我
ago that decision to kind of put my ego
决定暂时放下个人私心，这
aside for a bit was probably the
可能是
smartest decision I ever made the entire
我在Netflix期间做出的最明智的决定。
Netflix because those years after that
因为在那之后的几年里，
when Reed and I did it together that was
我和里德一起带领公司，迎来了Netflix的
the Renaissance at Netflix so many of
复兴。很多
the things that shaped what the company
塑造公司未来发展方向的因素都源于
during those years and certainly looking
那几年。当然，
since then since I left the company was
自从我离开公司后，里德为公司所做的一切
uh even more
更加令人
astounding and it's funny because one of
惊叹。有趣的是，
the roles of a CEO is you've got to make
CEO的职责之一就是
sure the best people are in the right
确保最优秀的人才
seats which means say goodbye to a lot
各司其职，这意味着要和很多人说再见。
of people you'll have someone You Who
你会遇到一些在
Came at when you started the company and
你公司创立之初就加入的同事，
they were your head of marketing and
他们是你的市场营销主管，
they worked tirelessly they worked
他们不知疲倦地工作，
weekend they work nights they did
周末加班，晚上也工作，你让他们做什么他们都去做。
everything you asked but as you get to a
但是，随着公司规模的扩大，情况就
different scale you recognize that
不同了。 你意识到这个
person is not the right person for what
人并不适合
we have to do next but you never think
我们接下来要做的事情，但你永远不会想到自己也需要审视
yourself um and I think a lot
自己。嗯，我认为很多
of Founders need to ask themselves that
创始人需要不断地问自己这个
question question all the time I'm the
问题：我
right person for yesterday I might even
昨天是合适的人选，
be the right person for today but am I
今天也可能是合适的人选，但我明天还是合适的人选吗？
number of Founders that I can think of
我能想到的创始人中，有多少人——
and I'll bet you you will Echo this when
我敢打赌，当
you think about all the founders you've
你回想所有你
spoken to who are great early stage
接触过的、优秀的早期
entrepreneurs and great late stage
创业者和后期
entrepreneurs it's a very very small set
创业者时，你也会有同样的感受？其实非常非常少。
um and in my case uh I was very very
嗯，就我而言，我非常非常
comfortable recognizing that this was
肯定地认为这
the right thing to do for the company
对公司来说是正确的选择。
when you when you think back to that
当你回想起那
moment and that conversation with Reed
一刻，回想起和里德的那次谈话，
where he comes into your office with
他带着
your hindsight and wisdom now do you
你的经验和智慧走进你的办公室时，你
think there's a better way that he could
觉得他当时有没有更好的处理方式？
situation of course Reed as I mentioned
当然有。正如我
before what made Reed and I work so well
之前提到的，里德和我之所以合作得如此默契，是因为
together as we were left brain and right
我们一个是左脑型，一个是右脑型，
brain and that's not Reed's strong suit
而这并非里德的强项。
um that's my strong suit you know I
嗯，这是我的强项，你知道，我擅长
pitch I know how to frame things in the
推销，我知道如何恰当地表达观点，
right way I know how to deliver bad news
我知道如何传达坏消息，
I know how to uh communicate effectively
我知道如何有效地沟通，
and I can intuitively know what's going
而且我能凭直觉判断什么会
to upset someone or not upset someone
惹恼别人，什么不会。这
that's not what Reed's great at but what
并不是里德的强项，但
Reed has and what we share is he cares
里德拥有的，也是我们共同拥有的，是他很关心公司。
Reed was doing
里德这样做
this not with some ulterior motive this
并非出于什么不可告人的目的，他
was not I want to push Mark out and
不是想把马克挤出局自己当
become CEO this was he genuinely
CEO，而是真心
believed this was the right thing for
相信这对公司来说是正确的。
the company and because we had this
因为我们之间有着
extremely strong relationship based on
基于信任的极其牢固的关系，所以我能
trust I heard him that way and
感受到这一点。从根本上来说，
fundamentally that's way more important
这比
delivered what was it that he thought he
表达方式重要得多。他认为自己
had that would suit the company in the
拥有什么，能够帮助公司在
next phase of the company's Journey that
下一阶段发展，而
he felt you didn't have he had already
你却不具备？他已经
taken a company through an IPO he had
带领一家公司成功上市，他
already scaled a company from two
已经把一家公司从两名
employees up to a thousand employees
员工发展到一千名员工，
from a local company to a multinational
从一家本地公司发展成为一家跨国公司。
company uh he had he had already shown
他已经证明
that he could hire extremely talented
他能够招募到非常优秀的
people to work for him he wasn't saying
人才为他工作。他并不是说…… 我当时
that he didn't think I it was impossible
并不认为
for me to do this
我做不到这一点，
and who knows would have happened this
谁知道会发生什么呢？这一切都关乎
was all about what increases our odds
如何提高我们
for success and then perhaps if you want
成功的几率。然后，如果你想
to drill down to something which in the
深入探讨一些事情，从
big scheme of things is small but in the
大局来看可能微不足道，但在
time was large is we had to raise
当时却意义重大，那就是我们必须筹集
money uh Netflix was a very very
资金。Netflix 的
expensive company to get started we
启动成本非常非常高，我们
required large amounts of venture money
需要大量的风险投资。
and Reed had this reputation of someone
里德·马歇尔 (Reed Mashall)
for some VCS because of taking his prior
之前就带领他的公司上市，已经为一些风险投资公司赚了很多钱，所以
company public and they would bet on him
他们愿意投资他。
whereas I was a little bit more of an
而我当时还不太出名。
unknown one of the things you talk about
你
in your book that he said to you in that
在书中提到，他在那次谈话中对你说，
conversation is you don't appear tough
你看起来不够强硬
and candid enough to hold strong
和坦率，无法赢得
people's
人们的
respect yeah it's um I'm better at that
尊重。是的，嗯，我
now does that count uh it is the empathy
现在在这方面做得更好了。这算数吗？嗯，是同理心。
I as I said what makes direct marketing
正如我所说，
Marketing in general is an interesting
直销之所以有趣，是
discipline because it requires you to
因为你需要把
send something out and you're not going
东西寄出去，而你
to ever see the person's face as they
永远看不到收件人收到后的
react to it you're not going to be there
反应，你无法亲身参与其中。
as they're reading this and either
他们读到这些内容时，要么会感到
getting confused or
困惑，要么会感到
excited you have to imagine those things
兴奋。你必须设身处地地想象这些情景。
and as you're writing a direct response
当你撰写直效营销
letter you're picturing how is someone
信时，你要想象人们
going to react when they read these
读到这些内容时的反应，想象他们
they're watching this direct response
观看直效营销
television
电视
commercial that's a it's it's a gift in
广告时的反应。从
some ways and it's also a gift when it
某种意义上说，这是一种天赋。在销售和谈判方面，这也是一种天赋。在开口
before I say something I know how it's
之前，我就知道
they're going to react and I can cater
他们会有什么反应，我可以迎合他们的反应。
that but what it does mean is that when
但这确实意味着，当
something's going to really hurt
某些事情会真正伤害到
somebody it's really hard for me it's
别人时，对我来说真的很难，
very painful for me to deliver very bad
传递坏消息对我来说非常痛苦。
news I've never considered that before
我以前从未想过这一点，
but it does appear to be completely true
但似乎确实如此：
that people who are great
优秀的
marketeers um have therefore have
营销人员往往更有
empathy and therefore struggle more with
同理心，因此在
delivering bad news because they just
传递坏消息时也更难开口，因为他们更
have a better ability of putting
善于设
themselves in the other person's shoes
身处地为他人着想。
you feel it you feel it you know I've
你能感受到，你能感受到。你知道，
and as I said I've gotten way better at
正如我所说，我在这方面已经进步了很多，
it um I'd say I'm good at it now um I'm
我现在可以说我很擅长了。 我有时候会很
I can be a complete ass when I how does
混蛋，比如，该如何
someone train that muscle is there a way
锻炼这种能力？还有提升的空间吗？
to go you know if you think about how
想想
you went from where you were with that
你从以前到
to where you are now is there anything
现在的转变，有没有什么方法让
that's helped you stop being I guess a
你不再那么在意别人
little bit about people's feelings when
的感受？我已经
there's a big I've stopped searching for
不再寻找
a way to do it that doesn't
一种不
hurt and as as with most decisions a lot
伤人的方法了。就像大多数决定一样，
of times people get caught in this
人们常常陷入这种
paralysis where they're trying to come
僵局，试图找到一个所谓的“
up with some Solution that's an Optimum
最佳
solution and this is one more example of
解决方案”。这又是一个例子：
that is that you go this is going to
你会想，这会很
hurt it's going to hurt me I have to
痛苦，会让我痛苦，但我还是得
just do it anyway there's no way to
做，没办法
avoid this and for example you know
避免。举个例子，你知道，先说说
jumping way ahead there was T after this
T公司在这次
doc layoff which we'll talk about in
医生裁员之后的情况，我们稍后会谈到，
just I mean doc com crash which we'll
我是说，在医生网络崩溃之后，我们不得不裁员，
lay people off and I cry with every
每次裁员我都哭，
single one of them but I bring them in
但我还是把他们带回来，
and I gotten very very good at telling
而且我变得非常擅长告诉
people uh it's time to go
别人…… 该走了，
but doesn't mean that I don't
但这并不意味着我不难过。
hurt hardest
最难受的
thing let's hope that if you're a
事，希望如果你是
manager that's the hardest thing you
经理，这应该是你做过的最难的事。
do have you forgiven Reed
你原谅里德
for that that moment that day the way he
那天
delivered what he said
说的话了吗？
100% uh this is going to sound silly but
百分之百原谅。嗯，这听起来可能有点傻，但他的话是
it came from love it didn't come from
出于爱，不是出于
Madness or jealousy or
疯狂、嫉妒或
anger it as much as it was possible for
愤怒。尽管有各种各样的
something to hurt Reed in delivering bad
事情可能会伤害到里德，但跟我谈坏
news that's got to have been one of
消息肯定是
the toughest things he's had to do is
他做过的最难的事之一。
have that conversation with me and I
我非常
have so much respect for the fact that
敬佩他
he had the courage and discipline to say
有勇气和自律，他说：“
I've thought of something I could I've
我想到了一些办法，我想到了一种
thought of a way to mail the DVDs more
更便宜的DVD邮寄方式，我想到了一种……”
the no he goes I've thought of a way to
不，他接着说：“我想到了一种
make the company more successful but
让公司更成功的方法，但这真的会很
hurt what is it about Reed then that
伤人。”那么，里德身上究竟有什么特质让他如此
makes Reed successful because I asked
成功呢？因为我问的是
you the question about yourself but now
你自己的问题，现在让我们
to turn that on Reed what is it that
反过来问问里德，是什么让他如此成功？ 正是这一点
makes him so unique see you used the
让他如此独特。你
analogy for creativity earlier in our
之前在我们谈话中用创造力作比喻，说信息就像云一样，各种
connections and seeing that there are
联系像云一样，而
them Reed sees that stuff so well I
里德能看出它们之间的相互关联。我自
consider myself really good at that he's
认为在这方面已经很不错了，但他比
even better than I am he will have a
我更胜一筹。他会遇到一个
very complicated problem with many
非常复杂的问题，涉及很多
moving pieces and he'll jump immediately
环节，但他会立刻
to we can do this and I won't see that
想到我们可以这样做，而我可能要过一会儿才能看到这一点，
until a little bit later and then even
然后其他
everyone else sees it it's just an
人也会明白。这是一种
amazing ability to see how things might
惊人的能力，能够预见事情的发展走向，
shape about and which one is the right
并找到正确的
path to take uh extremely
方向。他极具
analytical um extremely
分析能力，而且极少受
non emotionally driven can make very
情绪影响，因此能够做出非常
very hard decisions because uh
艰难的决定，因为他
less driven by that by the emotional
很少受情绪左右。他真是太了不起了。那么
remarkable what about hard work does it
努力工作呢？它
matter
重要吗？
well since you ask it so simply I'd say
既然你问得这么简单，我会说不重要，
no or it certainly is not the most
或者说它肯定不是最
important thing in fact I think hard
重要的。事实上，我认为努力
work leading to success is a
工作就能成功是一个
myth that and let me let me give you two
神话。让我举两个
examples
例子。
okay um the first is to qualify what I
首先，为了更好地说明我的
mean um I work with a lot of as he spoke
意思，我和很多人一起工作，正如他所说…… 在
earlier before we actually began the
我们正式开始会议之前，我先聊了聊
session um about how younger people are
年轻人和
older people especially with career and
老年人在人生阶段上的差异，尤其是在职业发展方面，
how they think about it and um earlier
他们的想法也不同。
in my life I used to do triathlons you
我年轻的时候经常参加铁人三项，就是那种游泳、
then biking and then
骑车、
running and back when I used to do them
跑步的比赛。现在比赛方式已经
they don't do it quite the same way
不一样了，变成了
anymore it would be a mass water start
集体水上出发，
you have four or 500 people who with the
四五百人随着
gunun sounds and all 500 of them plow
一声枪响同时冲进
into the water
水里，而
simultaneously not a phase start and as
不是分段出发。
you can imagine it is a show you
你可以想象那场面有多混乱，你会被人踢来踢去，
goggles are being knocked off and you're
泳镜会被打掉，还会被
being held underwater and you quickly
按在水下。你很快就会
realize that if you want to be able to
意识到，要想在
survive in this Mass Dart you're going
这种集体出发的混乱中活下来，就必须在
to Sprint for those first four five 600
最初的四五百码（600米）里全力冲刺，争取冲到
front of the pack that you have open
队伍的最前面，这样才能有开阔的
water and in my opinion work life is
水域。在我看来，
kind of like that when you're younger
年轻的时候，工作就像这样，对未来一无所知，不得不
doing when you have to go down a lot of
走很多
false ends because you're not just
弯路。 因为你不仅要
productive you better work your ass off
高效，你还得拼命工作，
you better Sprint you better work three
你得全力冲刺，你
times harder than everybody else in the
得比公司里的其他人努力三倍，
company so it's
所以这
essential but
至关重要。但
ideally you get yourself far enough
理想情况下，你应该让自己
ahead that you recognize I can't can't
领先足够远，这样你才能意识到“我不能以这种
go at this pace for the entire te of the
速度完成整个
triathlon I needed to to get myself some
铁人三项”，我需要给自己一些
breathing room but now I can back off so
喘息的空间，现在我可以放慢脚步了。所以，是的，在
yeah at certain points in your career
你职业生涯的某些阶段，
you need hard work at certain points in
你需要努力工作；在
the trajectory of your business you need
你事业发展的某些阶段，你需要
hard work your
努力工作；比如在
fundraising you can't say oh we're
融资阶段，你不能说“哦，我们快要完成交易了，
closing around I'm taking vacation for
我要休假
two weeks uh we're doing m&amp;a I'm going
两周”，或者“我们正在进行并购，
to be uh I'm only going to work a couple
我只会工作几个
hour no you're going to have to grind it
小时”，不，你必须拼命努力，
but that's not the answer all right one
但这并不是答案。好的，再讲一个
more little story which is part two to
小故事，这是这个故事的第二部分，这也是
this which is why I say that it's a myth
为什么我说
for hard work um so during one part of
努力工作是个误区。在
my career I lived in Europe uh I was
我职业生涯的某个阶段，我住在欧洲，我为
doing International marketing for a big
一家大型软件公司做国际营销，
software company we had an office in
我们在巴黎有个办公室，
Paris uh I lived in Paris and but I was
我住在巴黎。 但我
meeting every week with the marketing
每周都要和
people in our other branches so probably
我们其他分公司的市场部人员开会，所以大概五天里有四天
four days out of five I was flying fly
我都在飞。一天飞
to Copenhagen one day then I'd fly down
哥本哈根，一天
to Milan then I might fly to London then
飞米兰，然后可能飞伦敦，
I might fly to Madrid in one week so I
一周内可能又飞马德里。所以我
spent a lot of time at the airport and
花了很多时间在机场。
um because I'm sometimes not that
嗯，因为我有时候不太
organized uh I'd be late and you would
有条理，所以经常会迟到。你会
find me just sprinting Down The
看到我穿着西装外套
Concourse in my uh in my Blazer and my
和
wool coat trying to desperately make the
羊毛大衣，在候机大厅里狂奔，拼命想赶上
plane and what I found out
飞机。我发现，
was that probably 49% of the time I'd
大概有49%的情况下，我到了
pull up to the gate and the plane was
登机口，飞机
delayed and i' have to wander onto the
延误了，我得慢慢地走上
plane no problem at all I could have
飞机，完全没问题，我拄着
made it on crutches and instead I'd sit
拐杖都能上去。结果，我只能坐在
there marinating in my sweat for another
那里汗流浃背地等一个
hour before the plane took off or the
小时飞机才起飞；
other 49% of the time I'd come sprinting
剩下的49%的情况下，我冲过
Down The Concourse and you'd see the
候机大厅，你会看到
plane halfway out in the runway about to
飞机已经停在跑道上，准备
take off and what I realized is didn't
起飞了。我意识到，
make a difference whether you ran for a
不管你是跑着去，结果都一样。 不管有
plane or not that you're either going to
没有飞机，要么你能成功，
make it or you weren't going to make it
要么你没能成功，
and that running didn't make the
奔跑并不能改变结果。
difference and I vowed then and there
我当时就发誓，
I'd never run for a plane again and I
我再也不会为了赶飞机而奔跑，而且我也确实做到了。
never have and I'm telling you that
我讲这个
story because it's a metaphor in that so
故事是因为它是一种隐喻。
many entrepreneurs spend all this time
很多创业者把所有时间都花在
running for planes they are up all night
奔跑上，他们整夜
polishing their deck they're reviewing
打磨演示文稿，审查
the work of people to make sure the
别人的工作以确保
spelling is correct they're
拼写正确，反复
double-checking every detail they are
检查每一个细节，他们
working so hard but I know from
非常努力。但我从
experience that it's like running for
经验中得知，就像奔跑一样，
plane most of the time doesn't make a
大多数时候都
difference you don't lose the deal at 2
无济于事。你不会因为
o'cl that morning because you didn't
凌晨两点没
check the fonts you lost that deal four
检查字体而丢掉那笔生意，而是
weeks ago when you didn't have some
四周前因为你的一些
fundamentals right or you just weren't
基本功没做好，或者你一开始就没选对
the right company to begin with no
公司而丢掉那笔生意。
matter how hard you worked you weren't
无论你多么努力，你都无法
going to change the
改变结果。而这正是
balance in your life as an entrepreneur
创业者保持生活平衡的关键：
is this recognition that if you're smart
认识到如果你明智地
about the things that you choose to
选择
focus on you make 99% of the difference
关注的事情，你就能更好地平衡事业和生活。 你就能决定99%的成败，
and that all that extra work does not
而那些额外的努力其实并不会
really change the outcome
真正改变结果。
any and in that analogy of running for
就像
the plane is the is the key thing to
赶飞机一样，关键在于提前做好更充分的
have just better prepared further
准备。
Upstream I you know if we stick to the
如果我们继续用这个
analogy just have made a better decision
比喻，比如提前出门，做出更好的决定，那么确实会有帮助。
yes it does absolutely I mean if you
我的意思是，如果你
want to make the plane you you know you
想赶上飞机，你就会
leave earlier and again it's not
早点出门。再说一遍，
sometime listen you're going to scroll
有时候，你得在
down The Concourse you not don't need to
候机楼里往下看，你不需要
run and if if the plane left on time
跑。如果飞机准点起飞，跑也没用；如果
difference if the plane's late running
飞机晚点，跑也没用。反正
you made it or didn't make it the amount
你最终要么赶上了，要么没赶上。很多
of times that running for it was the
时候，赶飞机就像是决定成败的关键因素，但实际上却很少见。
or not is like infantes so what's the
所以，
point of running and that's and I really
跑的意义何在呢？我
fundamentally believe that is that
坚信，
if I can be really smart about my which
如果我能明智地选择
problems I choose to focus on I'll make
关注哪些问题，就能改变结果。
the difference I do not need to get
我不需要
everything right because most things
事事都做到完美，因为大多数事情
don't make a difference some things do
无关紧要，只有有些事情会。
some things do and some of the the small
一些
things that made a difference to your
对你的业务产生重大影响的小细节，
business seem to have been discovered
似乎是在
through a process of sort of
不断
experimentation and failure when I look
尝试和失败的过程中发现的。
back through your story at you trying to
回顾你之前的故事，你努力让
get sort of Netflix to work and get
Netflix成功运营并实现
product Market fit you referenced it a
产品与市场的契合，你
second ago this idea of no late fees
刚才提到了取消滞纳金的想法，这
seem to be quite pivotal an idea you had
似乎非常关键。你
to remove the late fees I I find this
取消滞纳金的想法很
interesting because there's going to be
有意思，因为很多
entrepreneurs that build their idea and
创业者会建立起自己的想法，
then bang their head against the wall
然后碰壁，最终
and it doesn't work and then I hear so
失败。但我
often whether it's from Brian chesky at
经常听到，无论是Airbnb的Brian Chesky
Airbnb or from someone else Daniel at
还是
Spotify that there seemed to be this one
Spotify的Daniel，都提到过某个
change that was quite pivotal to their
改变对他们的
business at some point so my question
业务发展至关重要。所以我的问题是，
becomes like how do I know how do I find
我该如何找到这个关键
the thing so can you explain to me why
因素？你能解释一下为什么
this no late fees thing and and any of
取消滞纳金以及
these other small changes that change
其他一些改变格局的小改变如此重要吗？是
the game and how what was the system
什么系统引导
that led you to
你发现了这些？
them you know we're talking about really
我们现在讨论的是真正意义上的
finding product Market fit product
产品与
Market fit if I have to give a
市场的契合。如果要给产品与市场的契合下一个
definition is when you recognize you
定义，那就是当你意识到你
finally have something that customers
终于拥有了顾客
actually do want and it's recognized
真正想要的东西。 之所以能被认可，是
because all of a sudden the momentum of
因为
your business dramatically shifts all of
你的业务势头突然发生了戏剧性的转变，一切都
a sudden things go into high gear all of
突然加速运转，
a sudden iring customers is so much
突然间，吸引客户变得如此
easier all of a sudden they're sticking
容易，突然间，他们就一直留了下来。
around it's just this instantaneous oh
这简直是瞬间的“
my God we found it and up until that
天哪，我们找到了！”。在此之前，你一直在
point it is this constant struggle of
不断地
trying one thing after another trying to
尝试各种方法，努力一步步
increment your way closer and closer and
接近目标。
closer you know when I mentioned that um
你知道，我刚才提到这一点的时候，
you know at the beginning there wasn't a
你知道，在Netflix的初期，
lot of business model Innovation with
商业模式并没有太多创新。
Netflix we if you ordered a disc we
如果你订购了一张光盘，我们会把
mailed it to you we charge you a due
它邮寄给你，收取费用，并设定
give you a due date if you missed the
一个到期日。如果你错过了
due date we had late fees and the
到期日，我们会收取滞纳金。但
reality is the idea was ridiculous it
实际上，这个想法很荒谬，根本
didn't work um nobody would rent from us
行不通。没有人会从
and if you did rent from us once you
我们这里租碟，即使租过一次，也
didn't rent from us again um and we kind
不会再租了。我们
of had this realization that okay we got
意识到，好吧，我们必须
to begin figuring things out and thus
开始想办法了。于是，我们
began this year and a half long process
开始了长达一年半的探索过程，
of trying to figure out some way to get
试图找到一种方法让
people to rent DVDs by mail from us and
人们通过邮寄的方式从我们这里租DVD。
and we tried almost everything you could
我们几乎尝试了你能
think of um hundreds of things and um I
想到的一切方法，成百上千种。 嗯，我经常
kind of talk about this a bunch
提到这一点，
that I had no shortage of ideas I mean I
我当时并不缺乏想法，我的意思是，我
had lots of things I wanted to try and
有很多想尝试的东西。
if there was any if there was a problem
如果说有什么问题的话，那就是
that I had it was that I was a bit of a
我当时有点
perfectionist back then and so all these
完美主义，所以所有
tests that I'd want to run I'd want them
我想做的测试我都希望它们
to be perfect so we would you know
完美无缺。我们会
lovingly argue over every word of copy
仔细斟酌每一个文案，
and we would do custom photography and
我们会定制照片，
we would check every link and we'd
我们会检查每一个链接，我们会对
stress test the site and it might take
网站进行压力测试。准备一次测试可能需要
us three weeks or a month to prepare for
三周甚至一个月的时间。
this test and we' test this new idea and
我们测试这个新想法，
then it would not work wouldn't do
结果却失败了，什么反应都没有。
anything and we'd kind of look at each
我们互相看着
other and go we just wasted a month so
对方，心想：我们白白浪费了一个月。
okay faster and then we do a test in two
好吧，那就快点。然后我们两周后再测试一次，结果还是
weeks and it would still fail okay okay
失败了。好吧，那就快点。我们
faster and we do it in a week and faster
一周后再测试一次，速度更快了。
we eventually started getting to the
最终，我们开始
point we could do do a test every day or
可以每天进行一次测试，甚至
multiple tests every day and it turns
一天进行多次测试。但事实
out that um once you go that fast things
证明，一旦速度这么快，事情就会
get very very sloppy so we would have
变得非常非常马虎。比如，我们会用
the wrong image or it would have the
错图片，或者图片
watermark on it or the pages we had
上有水印等等。 我们之前做的那些页面仍然会很糟糕，
greed would still be greeked you know
你知道，
not uh we'd have bad links we'd crash
不会有链接失效，不会导致
the site and then but that was such an
网站崩溃。但这对
incredibly big insight for us because it
我们来说是一个非常重要的发现，因为事实证明，即使
even spending a month crafting this
花一个月的时间
perfect test wasn't going to make it a
精心设计测试，如果一个想法本身是坏的，它也不会变成
good idea but if it had even an inkling
好主意。但如果它哪怕有一丝
of being a good idea no matter how bad
好主意的苗头，无论测试结果多么糟糕，
would immediately perk their head up
都会立刻引起用户的注意。
they'd raise their hand they fight to do
他们会举手，会争相尝试，会
it they'd call us they'd reboot the site
打电话给我们，会重启网站。
it was this incredibly loud signal that
这是一个非常强烈的信号，表明其中必有价值。
there was something there and it goes
这又
back to what we said before which is
回到了我们之前所说的，关键
that it's not about having a good idea
不在于拥有一个好主意，而
it's about building this whole process
在于建立一套完整的流程
and this culture and this system to try
、一种文化和一套系统，去尝试
lots of bad ideas and we got really
大量的坏主意。我们非常擅长
really good at trying lots of bad ideas
尝试大量的坏主意，
one after another hundreds of them each
一个接一个，成百上千个，每
one informing us to some little some
一个都给我们提供一些关于下一步该
little bit about what to try next and
尝试什么的信息。
eventually we got to this point where we
最终，我们剩下
had these two big Ideas left and one of
两个重要的想法，其中一个
them was uh at that point uh Netflix was
就是…… 呃，Netflix当时规模
pretty big we had probably in our
很大，我们的仓库里可能有
warehouse several hundred thousand DVDs
几十万张DVD。
and I remember one day we were Reed and
我记得有一天，我和里德
I were in the warehouse and looking at
在仓库里看着
all these DVDs and going it's such a
这些DVD，心想：这么多
shame that all these DVDs are here in
DVD堆在这里真是太可惜了。 那些闲置的
the warehouse where they're not doing
物品对
anyone any good I wonder if there's a
任何人都没有好处，我在想能不能把
way to store them at our customers
它们存放在客户
houses let them keep them and then when
家里，让他们一直用着，用完
they're done they mail it back we'll
寄回来，我们再换新的。与其
pay each time they replace it let's just
每次更换都收费，不如收取
have a monthly fee a subscription and
月费，让
they can rent as often as they want
他们可以无限次租借，
there's no due dates and no late fees
没有到期日，也没有滞纳金。
and it was a ridiculous idea but when we
这想法听起来很荒谬，但
tested it it was that mythical product
测试之后，它竟然真的实现了
Market fit it it worked people loved it
市场契合度，效果惊人。人们非常喜欢，根本停不下来，还
they couldn't get enough of it they told
告诉
their friends they did not cancel their
朋友们自己没有取消
subscriptions what part of it worked and
订阅。到底是什么环节奏效了？
why did it work God knows yeah but in in
为什么会成功？天知道。但事后看来，
retrospect what it did was it
它把
took one of Netflix's
Netflix
biggest impediments and turned it into
最大的障碍之一变成了
one of its biggest
最大的
assets you know we referred to my book
优势之一。我们参考了我的书，书名叫《这
it's called that will never work and
永远行不通》，之所以叫《这永远
will never work work it it's because
行不通》，是因为
when I pitched the idea and they had two
当我提出这个想法时，每个人都这么说，
reasons why they said it um and one of
他们给出的理由有两个。其中一个
course was uh streaming they said oh
当然是…… 他们说流媒体
it's a digital medium it's just a matter
是数字媒介，用不了
of days before everyone's streaming
几天，大家都会用流媒体，
these who needs DVDs and we realized
谁还需要DVD？但我们意识到
that was not the case it was inevitable
并非如此，流媒体的普及是不可避免的，
but it could be years but the other
但可能需要几年时间。另一个
reason was was Blockbuster why on Earth
原因是百视达（Blockbuster）的模式。
would anybody want to order a movie have
谁会愿意订购电影，等
it mailed to them get it 3 days later uh
三天后收到，
and then keep it a week and mail it back
然后放一个星期再寄回去呢？
when you can drive to a Blockbuster in
开车20分钟就能到百视达，
20 minutes and have the movie immediate
立刻就能看完，何乐而不为？
gratification and what happened when we
我们推出
did the no due dates no late fees is it
无到期日、无滞纳金的政策后，情况发生了
shifted because before with an all a
变化。以前用购物
cart system you would order it yeah you
车系统，要么订购电影，
get it three days later or you drive to
三天后收到，要么开车
Blockbuster in 20 minutes but now when
20分钟去百视达。但现在
it was no due dates no late fees you
没有到期日、无滞纳金，你
could order your movies they'd sit on
可以订购电影，它们就放在
top of your TV you keep them as long as
电视机上，想看多久就看多久。
this lag time is
这种延迟是
zero compared to 20 minutes to go to
零，而去
Blockbuster because you could order a
百视达要花20分钟。因为你可以一次
couple I imagine three you could order
订购两张，我想
three okay and so you always had
三张都行，这样你总有电影可
something to watch when you're done you
看。 你
put it in the mail and instantly you
把它寄出去，
know two days later another one replaces
两天后就能立刻知道另一张光盘已经送到了。
it so all of a sudden we weren't two and
所以突然之间，我们不再比
a half days slower than Blockbuster we
百视达慢两天半，而是
were faster faster than
比
Blockbuster and I think that was the
百视达快得多。我认为这就是
convenience and the thing is that when
便利之处。关键在于，
we did the analysis at the beginning
我们一开始分析
about Blockbusters Achilles heel it was
百视达的致命弱点时，发现那就是滞纳金。
the late fees everyone hated them uh
每个人都讨厌滞纳金，
that was the single biggest thing that
这是
people would say about Blockbuster I
人们对百视达最大的抱怨。我们
hate the late fees and by being able to
讨厌滞纳金，而能够
get rid of that it was a huge
取消滞纳金是一个巨大的
competitive advantage and it was baked
竞争优势。滞纳金已经深深嵌入
into the Blockbuster business model they
百视达的商业模式中，他们
couldn't easily
很难
get out of it again so for someone that
再摆脱它。所以，对于
might not be aware of Blockbuster the
可能不了解百视达的人来说，
late fees are if I didn't bring back
滞纳金是指如果我没有归还
this tape of this movie I would get
这部电影的录像带，就会
charged per hour or per day or something
按小时或按天收取费用。
yeah it's usually three or four dollars
通常每天要三四美元，这
a day okay which is a lot of money for a
对于一张DVD来说可是一笔巨款。
that but it was also this feeling of uh
但同时，也有一种感觉，那就是，
I was okay paying the initial fee to
我本来可以接受支付初始租金来
rent the movie because I want but now
租这部电影，因为我喜欢它，但现在
I've watched the movie and I just
我已经看过这部电影了，而且…… 就是
couldn't get it back in time and now oh
没能及时还回去，
my God now I got to pay more just to
现在天哪，我居然还要额外付费才能还
return it it just felt like this
回去！感觉就像是
unwarranted unpleasant punishment for
对顾客莫名其妙的惩罚。
the customer I was thinking about
我想起了
something that Daniel conman the famous
丹尼尔·卡曼（Daniel Carman）——那位著名的
sort of psychologist um talked about in
心理学家——在
his paper when he wrote about loss
他的论文里提到的损失厌恶。简单来说，
didn't read part of this is that Daniel
丹尼尔·
Carman discovered that people have a
卡曼发现人们
real disdain for feeling like they've
非常厌恶失去
lost something and in his studies he
东西的感觉。他的研究
shows that if you drop $10 on the floor
表明，如果你不小心把10美元掉在地上，
you don't need to find $10 to make up
你不需要再找10美元来弥补
for the pain of losing 10 you'd actually
损失的痛苦，你实际上
need to find 20 or 30 and and so he has
需要找20美元甚至30美元。他画了
this wonderful graph where he talks
一张很棒的图表，说明对
about that we just loss to us is so much
我们来说，损失远比获得
more painful than a gain so in the case
更痛苦。就拿百视达（
of Blockbuster a late fee is is is money
Blockbuster）来说，滞纳金就是我白白损失的钱，对吧？
it's not losing $4 in in the context of
损失的不是4美元，而是
it's actually losing like $12 it's that
12美元，就是这么
painful exactly it was it was a really
痛苦。真的，我非常非常
really hated aspect of the video rental
讨厌这种感觉。 当时的录像带租赁
experience back then and also it made me
体验让我
think about the peak and which is you
想到了“巅峰体验”的概念，也就是优步
their Labs where they say that people
实验室发现的那个现象：人们往往在
experience and so if my end of an
体验的结尾处记住巅峰体验。如果我在
experience with Blockbuster is getting
百视达的体验最终是被
charged getting punished that's really
收费、被罚款，那真是太
interesting I've never heard that before
有趣了，我以前从未听说过这种说法，
but that fits entirely it was the
但这完全符合我的预期。在
with Blockbuster is to go in and have
百视达的体验最完美的标志就是进去之后，
someone say thanks for returning your
有人说“谢谢您归还
movie now you owe us $8 or $12 just like
电影，现在您欠我们8美元或12美元”，这简直是
a horrible end experience custom and
糟糕透顶的体验。
that's why I think a no no due dates no
这就是为什么我认为取消
late fees
逾期付款和滞纳金
was so profoundly game-changing for us
对我们来说意义如此重大，
and it marked the beginning of that that
它标志着公司转型的开始，在
for the next five or six seven years and
接下来的五六七年里，公司的发展方向发生了翻天覆地的变化。
it was more than just no duties late
这不仅仅是取消
fees but the transition to a
滞纳金和滞纳金，向
subscription business was huge and this
订阅模式的转型更是意义非凡。
is you know now everything's a
你知道，现在几乎所有东西都是
subscription business every piece of
订阅模式，
software you buy is a subscription every
你买的每款软件都是订阅，所有东西都是
everything subscription back then that
订阅。但当时
was not the case uh there was book clubs
并非如此，比如有订阅制的读书俱乐部，还有
which were subscription there was record
唱片
and tape clubs of subscription there was
和磁带俱乐部。 订阅模式以前只有
magazines and that's all and in some
杂志，仅此而已。从某种程度上来说，
ways when you look back at what some of
回顾
the huge Netflix Innovations were one of
Netflix的一些重大创新，其中之一就是
them was demonstrating you could apply
证明了订阅模式可以应用于
subscription to something which is
一些看似反
unintuitive and it came from this fact
直觉的领域。这又源于
my past that I happen to had a year and
我过去一段看似无关的经历：我曾有一年
a half of experience really
半的时间真正
understanding subscription economics
理解订阅经济，并着眼于未来。
when you were looking forward so I I'm
所以，我对
so fascinated by this test that you did
你做的那个改变Netflix命运的测试非常着迷。
there's a couple of them that you've
你
described but when you did you know
提到过几个类似的测试，但你当时并没有预料到
looking forward that it would have that
它会产生如此巨大的
much of an impact and I'm saying this
影响。我这么说是
because that helps me to understand
因为这让我明白，
whether I should just conduct a a lot
我应该继续做
more tests or I should do what I think
更多测试，还是应该像
most companies do where we sit in a
大多数公司那样，坐在
boardroom and we spend hours and hours
会议室里花几个小时
trying to find the perfect test is the
试图找到完美的测试方法？答案是：继续
game just conduct more tests if I didn't
做更多测试。如果我
have to sit by the microphone I'd get up
不用坐在麦克风前，我真想站起来敲
and hit you upside the head for that
你的脑袋，就因为你刚才那
comment God no you should not be sitting
句话！天哪，你不应该坐在
in the boardroom debating what to do you
会议室里讨论该怎么做，你
should be running more tests you should
应该去领导公司。 你应该进行更多测试，你应该
always be running more tests you don't
不断进行更多测试。你什么都不
know you don't know I mean you
知道，你什么都不知道，我的意思是，你
don't your customers do but they even
不知道，你的客户知道，但他们自己
they don't know what they want and the
也不知道他们想要什么，而
only way to figure it out is to throw
弄清楚这一点的唯一方法就是把
all kinds of things at them and see what
各种各样的东西都抛给他们，看看他们对哪个
direction
方向
they're interested in but so did I have
感兴趣。但是，我当时真的知道
any idea subscription was a big thing
订阅会这么火吗？
absolutely not and once it began to work
绝对没有。一旦它开始奏效，而且效果
and it worked like crazy we still had no
惊人，我们仍然不
idea how to optimize it and we Netflix
知道如何优化它。20
still 20 plus years later spends ungodly
多年过去了，Netflix仍然花费
amounts of time on testing all kinds of
大量时间测试
things about subscription Dynamics what
订阅动态的方方面面，比如如何
does it take to get someone to do it
让人们订阅，如何
what does it take to get someone to stay
让人们继续订阅，这些因素的
what influence is these it's
影响是什么。这
unbelievably complex but it's
极其复杂，但也
unbelievably important but subscriptions
极其重要。订阅之所以
there's a reason why it's it's eating
风靡
the world it's an incredibly compelling
全球是有原因的，它是一种极具吸引力的
business model and uh the fact that we
商业模式。我们
stumbled onto it and that it worked so
偶然发现了它，而且它效果如此之
well just was a very very positive uh
好，这真是一件非常非常积极的事情。
thing you know it's interesting on the
关于
testing point just to close off there I
测试这一点很有意思。最后，我想说的是，我
embodying the position of most companies
体现了…… 大多数公司
or employees or Founders listening to
、员工或创始人之所以
this the reason why they don't want to
不愿
run tests or don't have a culture of it
进行测试或缺乏测试文化，
is because it involves failure and
是因为测试意味着失败，而
failure then in most companies results
失败在大多数公司会导致互相
in blame and blame makes people feel bad
指责，指责会让人感觉糟糕，从而打击积极性。
so it disincentivizes them but creating
但是，要创造
a culture where failing is a positive
一种将失败视为积极因素并加以
and it's celebrated is quite a challenge
鼓励的文化，确实是一个不小的挑战。
career for me I mean I uh I do a lot of
对我来说，这简直就是我的职业。我经常在
over the world and a lot of them are big
世界各地进行公开演讲和主题演讲，其中很多都是面向大型
companies who are going our whole
企业的。我们整个
world's being turned upside down our
世界都在经历翻天覆地的变化，我们的
whole Workforce is risk of
整个劳动力都面临着风险。
Mark get in here and help us figure out
马克，请你来帮我们想想
how to make everyone a bit more risk
如何让每个人都更能
tolerant but you know what do they do uh
承受风险。但你知道他们会怎么做吗？他们会说：“好的，马克，
they'll go okay Mark your theme today is
你今天的主题是，
we're trying to get everyone to be
我们要让每个人都成为
bigger Risk Takers to take chances we
更大的风险承担者，敢于冒险，我们
want to celebrate
要庆祝
risk uh so but before you go on we're
风险。” 但在你继续之前，我们要
going to celebrate the sales leaders and
表扬一下销售主管，
bring them up and reward them for the
让他们上台，并奖励他们
trips to Hawaii it it's like you said
去夏威夷的旅行。就像你说的……
you have to let people know that
必须让人们知道，
failling is not not only okay it's
失败不仅可以接受，
expected and it's a good thing and we
而且是意料之中的，甚至是一件好事。我们
found we we learn from it and I don't
发现，我们可以从失败中学习。
even cons listen I don't even consider
我甚至不认为那是
it failures they're not failures they're
失败，它们不是失败，而是测试。这些测试
tests that didn't necessarily work but
不一定成功，但
they worked in the sense that you learn
它们确实有效，因为你从中学习到了一些东西，
something from them and you just keep
然后你一遍又一遍地重复
doing those over and over again and
这些测试。
again if you go back to this my first
如果你回到我的第一个
principle is how do you learn how to do
原则，那就是如何学习进行
tests which are quick cheap and easy you
快速、廉价且简单的测试，你
can do tons of them talking about giving
可以进行大量的测试。说到
speeches there just a week before the do
演讲，就在
com Bubble Burst you gave a speech in um
互联网泡沫破裂前一周，你在
New York City and your dad was there
纽约市发表了一次演讲，你父亲也在场。
yeah my dad was the anti-
是的，我父亲是个反
entrepreneur uh he was extremely risk
创业者，他极其厌恶风险，
averse uh he was an investment adviser
他是一名投资顾问，
people in a company whose whole
在一家公司为人们管理资金，这家公司的全部
principle was fundamentals long
原则是基本面，
long-term value he had no clue
长期价值。他完全不明白
whatsoever about why I was doing what I
我为什么要做我
was doing and this whole Venture world
正在做的事情，整个风险投资界
it was just completely made no sense to
对他来说完全没有意义。
him um but that speech in New York City
但是，在纽约市的那次演讲
was actually
实际上……
fairly interesting because what I was
挺有意思的，因为我当时在
doing was speaking to the DVD
给DVD
manufacturers Association I think it was
制造商协会做演讲，我想是
about what we' learned about more
关于我们如何更
effective ways to expand their
有效地拓展
business and on one hand I think my dad
业务。一方面，我觉得我爸
was extreme ex proud to see that all the
特别自豪，因为他看到
stuff that I'd been saying which he
我之前说的那些他
thought was all a bunch of
觉得都是
hooie was actually important and
胡扯的东西，现在居然
interesting to people but unfortunately
对大家来说这么重要、这么有意思。但不幸的是，
it was also um he happened to be in New
他当时正好在
York that time to get treatment for a
纽约接受脑瘤治疗，
brain tumor which he had just realized
他刚发现
he had and um so it kind of was this
自己得了脑瘤。所以，这算是
beginning of this my dad understanding
我爸第一次真正理解
time what I was good at
我擅长什么的开始，同时也是
of not of our relationship but it marked
我们父子关系的结束，但标志着我们不得不和
him so it was kind of this very very
他告别。那真是一段非常非常
Bittersweet uh Bittersweet
苦乐参半的
time in 2000 at 42 years old when you
时光。2000年，你
were 42 years old um he just just one
42岁，就在互联网
week before the dot crash your father
泡沫破裂前一周，你的父亲
passes away right I mean the timing is
去世了，对吧？我的意思是，这个时间点真是
um is is extremely unfortunate but also
太不幸了，
perspective to lose their father at that
失去父亲对一个人的影响肯定非常巨大。
that in that season of Life yeah I guess
人生总有起伏，我想
it's part of you go well what else can
这是你人生的一部分，你会想，还能有什么
go wrong and you find out
更糟的呢？然后你会发现
plenty
糟透了。
but the tragic this is going to sound
但悲剧的是，
tried I suppose but one of the tragic
我知道这话听起来很老套，但
things about my father dying before the
我父亲在互联网泡沫破灭前去世，其中一个悲剧之处在于，
dot collapse is he missed seeing that he
他没能看到自己是
right he missed seeing that in fact this
对的。他没能看到，事实上，那些
companies commanding these ridiculous
公司
valuations with no revenues and even
估值高得离谱，却没有收入，
even less profit um which he thought he
利润更少，他
could not understand how this could
无法理解这一切怎么
possibly be real well as we all found
可能是真的。但
out a week later it wasn't real
一周后，我们都发现这一切都是假的。
and I think he would have really loved
我想，如果他能看到自己是对的，他一定会非常高兴。
um but it was kind of this double hit
但对我来说，这简直是双重打击。
death of my dad and then all of a sudden
父亲的去世让我悲痛欲绝，突然间又要
having to worry now about the death of
担心公司的倒闭。
losing your father on what matters in
失去父亲是否改变了你对
life
人生意义的看法？
I'm gonna say no
我想说没有。
because what was great about my father
因为我父亲最棒的地方
was that he was very true to
在于他非常忠于
himself he was very comfortable being an
自我，他很坦然地接受自己作为一位
iconic clast about holding different
特立独行的
opinions uh even as we just mentioned
偶像，即使我们…… 就像我之前提到的，
bubble when everyone else was saying
当所有人都说“Do”
this was the next big thing and he's
是下一个爆款的时候，他却觉得
going this makes no sense whatsoever and
这完全没道理，但
he held to it and he lived his whole
他坚持了自己的想法，并且一生都这样生活。
way and so in some ways when he died
所以，在某种程度上，他去世的时候，人们感受到了一种
there was this sense that it is possible
信念：忠于
be true to yourself and um and be
自我，获得
fulfilled that you do not need to chase
满足感，而无需追逐
the trends was reminding me that
潮流。这让我想起了我自己，
I was like um and I was probably
大概
22 my first real job where I actually
22岁的时候，我开始第一份正式工作，
had to go sit in an office uh my dad
需要坐在办公室里。我爸
called me into the
把我叫到书房，从一张
den um and tore a page off of a yellow
黄色便笺纸上撕下一页，上面用
pencil the Randolph rules of
铅笔写着“兰道夫
success and he goes this these are the
成功法则”。他说：“这些是
things that I have learned over my
我
career as a business person and I think
作为一名商人，在职业生涯中学到的东西。
I want you to see these as you start
我希望你们在开始职业生涯的时候也能看到这些法则。” 我当时
was looking at them and what was
看着这些法则，心里有点忐忑，不知道该期待些什么。
interesting was that these were not
有趣的是，这些法则并不是
business rules this wasn't like you know
商业规则，不是那种“
Buy Low and sell high or happiness is
低买高卖”或者“幸福就是
positive cash flow or anything like that
正现金流”之类的。
these were basically rules that said
这些基本上是一些规则，它们告诉你，
it's possible to be a decent person and
做一个正直的人也能获得
still be successful I mean it was simple
成功。我的意思是，都是些很简单的
things like you know do 10% more than
事情，比如多做10%的工作，要
prompt it was um don't knock don't
准时，不要抱怨，要坚持
complain stick to constructive serious
建设性的
criticism it was don't express opinions
批评，不要对你不了解事实的事情发表意见。
mean that's who my dad was that he um
我爸爸就是这样的人，他
felt that those were the important
觉得这些是需要
things to communicate to me which is
传达给我的重要信息，那就是：做一个正直的人。
then the dotom bubble happens most of us
然后，泡沫经济出现了，我们大多数人都
can't remember I think I was how old was
记不清了，我想我当时几岁？大概
I must have been seven or seven or so
七岁左右吧，
seven years old so I can't really
所以我不太
remember what happened yeah but I know
记得发生了什么。是的，但我知道情况很
bad well it was especially bad for us I
糟糕，对我们来说尤其糟糕。
we were talking a moment ago about
我们刚才还在讨论
subscriptions and how subscription
订阅模式，以及订阅
economics are amazing and what makes
经济有多么神奇。
them amazing is that you acquire your
它的神奇之处在于，你获得一个
customer and then that customer gives
客户后，这个客户会在接下来的
you money for months after afterwards
几个月甚至几年里持续付费。
afterwards but because a subscription
因为订阅
customer is willing to give you money
客户愿意在
for years afterwards you can invest more
未来几年里持续付费，所以你可以投入更多资源
in acquiring that customer you can spend
来获取这个客户，比如花
$100 to bring that customer on board
100美元就能让他加入你的团队。 他们
with the confidence they're going to
自信地认为，
give you $10 a month month after month
每个月都会给你10美元，月复一月，月
after month after month but it means in
复一月，月复一月。但这意味着，第一个月
month one you spent 100 and you made
你花了100美元，只赚了
10 so when you have a subscription
10美元。所以，当你的订阅
business which is booming which is going
业务蓬勃发展，
crazy when customers are flooding in the
客户蜂拥而至时，
door well money is flooding out the door
资金也随之流失。
the cash required to service those bring
服务
those customers in for their first month
这些客户所需的现金，以及吸引他们第一个月的
huge the revenue from them not so much
巨额收入，都会让你损失惨重。更
not to mention we had a first month free
何况，我们还有首月免费
policy and that wasn't a problem in uh
政策，这在
2000 that was the era of irrational
2000年3月还不是问题。那是一个非理性
exuberance that was where you had these
繁荣的时代，一些
companies where had no Revenue no real
公司没有收入，也没有真正的
business model worth hundreds of
商业模式，却价值数亿
millions of dollars where I could go out
美元。我仿佛可以拿着
on the highway with a green flag and
绿旗在高速公路上挥舞，
wave it and a dump truck of money would
一辆装满钱的卡车就会
pull off and back up to my driveway and
停在我家门口，
I just need to come out with the
我只需要用
wheelbarrows and bring the money in it
手推车把钱运回来就行了。这简直太
was ridiculous until the dotom crash and
荒谬了。直到互联网泡沫破裂，一切
all of a sudden in a matter of a week or
突然在一两周内
two completely dried up and all of a
彻底崩溃，
sudden having a.com on your name was no
拥有一个.com域名也
longer the road to riches it was The
不再是通往成功的捷径。 财富？那是《
Scarlet
红字》啊，
Letter um and we were in deep trouble we
嗯，我们当时处境非常糟糕，
were basically going to go broke being
基本上要破产了，即便
successful and when that happens as
成功了也一样。就像
you've seen with other entrepreneurs you
你在其他创业者身上看到的那样，当这种情况发生时，你会
do something called pursue strategic
采取一种叫做“寻求战略
Alternatives which is code for we have
替代方案”的做法，这其实就是“我们
got to sell this sucker
必须尽快把这烂摊子卖掉”的委婉说法。我们当时
fast and we had an obvious strategic
有一个显而易见的战略
alternative which was Blockbuster how
替代方案，那就是百视达。
you losing money at that point oh my God
你当时是怎么亏钱的？哦，我的天哪，是的，大概亏了
yes how much roughly uh at that point we
多少？嗯，当时我们
had accumulated losses of about $50
累计亏损了大约5000万美元，
million and you you you accumulated
而你们的收入是500万美元。你们的累计亏损是多少？
losses what was your sort of annual
你们的
yearly burn rate how much money were you
年烧钱率是多少？你们
burning every year uh well there we were
每年烧多少钱？嗯，我们当时才成立
business for 2 and a half years so it
两年半，所以
most of that 50 had been in the previous
那5000万美元的大部分都是在过去
12 months I mean that's I mean on paper
12个月里亏损的。我的意思是，从账面上看，
that's not a good business well not just
这绝对不是一个好的生意，不只是从账面上看，
on yeah it's a terrible business you
这简直是一个糟糕的生意。你
know they they say that one of the goals
知道，人们常说，
of any startup is to receive a
任何创业公司的目标之一都是获得一个
repeatable scalable business model that
可复制、可扩展的商业模式，但这
is not what we mean by repeatable
并不是我们所说的可复制、可
scalable business model um it's
扩展的商业模式，嗯，这简直是一场
disastrous and you have lots of
灾难。 很多
businesses which go we're going to make
企业都想着先靠
it up in volume or once we just get the
销量弥补损失，或者先吸引
get the eyeballs then we'll monetize it
眼球，然后再考虑盈利。但当
the opportunity for all those things
所有这些机会突然
goes away it's disastrous we're just
消失时，情况就变得非常糟糕，我们
completely upside down our economics did
的经济状况彻底颠覆了。
you go to Blockbuster or did they come
你是主动联系百视达的，还是他们主动找上门的？
to you no we tried going to Blockbuster
不，我们
for months we tried reaching out to them
尝试了好几个月主动联系他们，
but this was this ultimate listen we
但最终还是失败了。听着，我们年收入500万美元，
were doing five million a year they were
他们
doing $6 billion dollar a year okay so
年收入60亿美元。
you we had 150 employees they had
我们只有150名员工，他们有
60,000 that we were like a gat you know
6万名员工，我们就像他们眼中的“盖茨”，就像大象一样，他们
their tail flipped around what's this
摇尾巴，根本
no interest in US whatsoever it took
没兴趣。
months and finally we got the
我们等了好几个月，终于接到了他们的
call and as luck would have it we got
电话。幸运的是，我们接到
the call we were at a corporate retreat
电话的时候正在参加一个公司团建活动，
uh at a place called The alisol Ranch
地点
on the coast of California pretty rural
在加州海岸一个叫圣巴巴拉的城市，一个非常偏僻的山区。
mountains it's a dude ranch you know
那是一个度假牧场，你知道，有
horses so we're on Retreat and you also
马，所以我们在Retreat度假。你也
know that in silic and Valley that we're
知道，在硅谷，我们的穿着
pretty casual and when you're on Retreat
都很随意，在Retreat度假的时候，
you have to work at it to be even more
你还得刻意让自己看起来更
casual so all I had with me was shorts
随意。所以我当时只带了短裤、
uh t-shirts uh thong sandals you know
T恤和人字拖，你知道，就这些。就在这时，
that's when Blockbuster calls goes we'll
百视达打来了电话，说他们
like to see you tomorrow in
想明天在达拉斯见你。
Dallas and I remember turning to Reed
我记得我转头对里德说，这
and going there's no way uh we can't fly
不可能，我们不能从圣巴巴拉直飞，
time zones are different we can't
时区不一样，我们不可能
possibly get to Dallas by tomorrow and
明天就到达拉斯。
so we did the prudent thing you do when
所以我们做了个明智的选择，当
you're $50 million in the hole and we
你负债5000万美元的时候，我们
chartered a corporate
包了一架
jet uh a rounding error I think they
公务机，我想他们管这叫“四舍五入误差”。
call that uh we fly to Dallas um go up
我们飞到达拉斯，来到
to in the 27th 28th floor of this
这座
massive glass and steel skyscraper into
巨大的玻璃钢摩天大楼的27层或28层，进入一个
this huge cavernous conference room
巨大的会议室，
there's a big hardwood table made of I'm
那里…… 一张巨大的硬木桌子，我敢
sure out of some endangered Amazonian
肯定是用某种濒危的亚马逊
hardwood or something it was horrendous
硬木之类的做的，
the whole thing and I'm there in shorts
整个场景都糟透了。我穿着短裤
and a t-shirt and your thong sandals and
、T恤和人字拖，还有那双凉鞋，真让人
and the sandals and Reed I was jealous
羡慕。里德穿着
he had a Hawaiian shirt he had buttons
夏威夷衬衫，上面还有扣子，我当时都嫉妒死了。
anyway in come the Blockbuster guys and
总之，百视达的人来了，
we make our pitch we go we'll combine
我们开始做推介。我们说，我们会强强联合，
forces um you'll run the stores we'll
你们负责实体店，我们
run the online business we'll build a
负责线上业务，我们会建立一个
blended model which our research has
混合模式，我们的研究
shown is a
表明，这种模式会改变
GameChanger and everything will work out
游戏规则，一切都会好起来的。一切进展顺利，
and it was going good you know they were
你知道，他们
asking good questions they're leaning in
问了很多好问题，他们很认真地听，我们觉得一切都在顺利进行。
this is rolling and then they asked the
然后他们问了那个
big question you know how much and of
关键问题，你知道，多少钱？
course we'd rehearsed on the plane we
当然，我们在飞机上已经演练过了，我们
figured we're $50 million in the hole so
估计要亏5000万美元，5000万
$50
美元。
million and there's this silence in the
房间里一片寂静，
room and I'm looking at uh Blockbuster
我看着百视达的
exec trying to piece together what the
高管，试图弄清楚他们的
reaction is and it finally Dawns on me
反应，最后…… 我突然意识到，
they're trying to suppress
他们正努力憋
laughter they're trying trying to keep a
笑，努力保持
straight face at the hubris that this
面无表情，因为这
little company $50 million in debt at
家小公司在金融危机低谷期负债5000万美元，
the trough of the Meltdown could
却有
possibly be worth $50 million so as you
可能价值5000万美元，这简直太狂妄了。可想而知，在
quickly after that long quiet ride in
那漫长而沉默的出租车之旅后，会议很快就陷入了僵局。之后，在
the cab back to the airport even quieter
返回机场的飞机上，气氛更加沉闷。
Barbara and I I so profoundly remember
我至今仍清晰地记得，我
sitting there on the plane just my head
坐在飞机上，低着头，一句话也不说，
talking just thinking ah I I was so
沉默寡言。 啊，我当时非常
confident that if we just got the
自信，觉得只要能和他们
meeting that this Blended model was so
开会，他们就会用这个混合模式
self-evidently great that they'd save
拯救我们，这个模式显然非常棒。
us but now they weren't going to save us
但现在看来，他们不仅没能拯救我们，反而要和我们
they were going to compete with us and
竞争，
we were in trouble did they make you an
我们陷入了困境。他们给你
offer uh no they just rejected the $50
报价了吗？没有，他们拒绝了5000万美元的
million offer
报价。
and you know my Dad one of the things he
你知道，我爸
sometimes to say to me is like you know
有时会跟我说，
when I was struggling with some
当我遇到特别
particularly nasty problem and came to
棘手的问题，向
him for the solution he' go you know
他寻求解决方案时，他会说，
sometimes the only way out is through
有时候唯一的出路就是直面
that you got to take these problems and
问题，你必须迎难而上，
just go right at them there's no no way
没有捷径可走。
around and this was such a classic case
而这正是一个典型的例子，
of that there was no easy way out of
没有简单的出路，
this the only way we were going to
我们生存的唯一途径就是
survive was be to compete with them that
和他们竞争。为了
we could do that when we laid people off
做到这一点，我们裁员了，
we dropped entire lines of uh adjunct
放弃了整个业务线，
little businesses completely focused it
完全专注于核心业务，最终
in and and survived and eventually you
生存了下来。最终，你
know as eventually um passed Blockbuster
知道，我们超越了百视达，
and eventually um Blockbuster went into
而百视达最终
bankruptcy I don't know how Blockbuster
破产了。 百视达怎么
couldn't have just looked over and seen
可能眼睁睁看着
your business succeeding at some point
你的生意越来越好，然后说：“
and gone okay we've got 6 billion
好吧，我们每年有60亿美元的
Revenue a year which will just destroy
收入，这肯定会把你打垮，我们会用
them with advertising or something it's
广告之类的手段把你碾压过去。” 这就是
a big piece of innovators dilemma um in
创新者面临的一大困境。嗯，就他们而言，有
their case uh a couple things going on
几个因素在起作用。首先，
um number one imagine you are the CEO of
想象一下你是百视
Blockbuster okay called John wasn't it
达的CEO，名叫约翰·
John antioco so you've got6 billion
安蒂奥科（John Antioco），你
dollar coming in through your standard
通过标准的
business model which is serving these
商业模式——服务遍布
bricks and mortar stores all over the
全球的实体店——获得了60亿美元的收入。这时
and someone comes to you and goes we
有人来找你说：“我们
need to build an online component and
需要开发一个线上业务。”
John goes well what do you think that
约翰问：“你觉得
could do in Revenue the first year and
第一年能带来多少收入？” 你说：“
million so would you say okay take our
万美元。” 你会说：“好吧，把我们
very best
最好的
Engineers let's put them on this
工程师都派到这个
project no you go okay figure here's a
项目上来。” 不，你会说：“好吧，我们来算算，
hand figure it out and you could put the
你可以让
the B team is on it and of course it
二线团队来做。” 当然
doesn't Netflix wasn't a movie company
不会。Netflix 不是一家电影
company it was a software company I mean
公司，而是一家软件公司。我的意思是，
we had Silicon Valley we had people who
我们有硅谷，我们有那些
had spent their whole life building
投入巨资的人。 他们一辈子都在开发
software you can't compete with that
软件，就算他们组建一个团队，你也无法与他们竞争。
even with their a team it would have
这本来就很
been challenging but they put the B and
有挑战性，但他们派出了B组和
the C team on it and they did that a
C组，而且他们还进行了
second time and then a third time and
第二次、第三次尝试。
finally each time we're stronger and
最终，我们一次比一次强大，越来越
stronger and stronger and eventually
强大。最终，他们意识到必须
they go we got to fix this and they pick
解决这个问题，于是他们组建了
a team they resource it adequately they
一个团队，配备了充足的资源，然后说：“
say get out of the
离开
building go across town
公司，去城里另一边，把
set up here's the money come after these
钱给
guys and it's one of it's a story which
你们，来对付我们吧！”这是一个
has not really been told very well but
不太为人所知的故事，但
they came really really close to taking
他们真的差点就
down um Netflix they were in a they that
扳倒了Netflix。Netflix当时采用的是
Blended model which we knew was a
混合模式，我们知道这种模式非常
killer which a blended model means you
致命。混合模式意味着你
can rent from Blockbuster and you can
可以从百视达租借电影，然后可以选择
either return it in the mail or you can
邮寄还款、
return it at the store or you can go
到店还款、到
pick it up at the store or you can have
店取货或者
it mailed to you
邮寄到家。
and we couldn't compete with that we
我们根本无法与之竞争，因为我们
didn't know the
不了解百视达的
stores and it really really came close
门店。Netflix真的差点就
to taking Netflix down until all of a
垮掉了，直到
sudden they had all kinds of unrelated
突然间，他们发生了一系列与此无关的
corporate
公司内部
shenanigans that made them decide change
丑闻，最终导致他们决定更换
CEOs we're going to dource this online
CEO。 我们打算收购这家在线
business and walked away from it what
业务，然后就放弃了。
was I saw you talk about this on your
我最近在你的Instagram上看到你谈到这件事，
Instagram recently um when John quit the
嗯，就是John离开
business so John was the CEO of
公司的时候。John是
Blockbuster
百视达的CEO，
and him quitting the bussiness for a
他因为各种原因离开公司，
that you think Netflix actually ended up
你认为这在很大程度上促成了Netflix最终
not getting killed by Blockbuster
没有被百视达扼杀，对吗？
correct can you explain that so and I'm
你能解释一下吗？我可能记不太清了，
not going to get this entirely right but
但
there basically were people who are
基本上就是一些
corporate Raiders who would buy large
企业掠夺者会大量购买
amounts of a company's stock and take
一家公司的股票，然后占据
seats on the
董事会席位，
board um take multiple seats on the
嗯，占据多个席位，
board and begin to try and dictate
开始试图左右
things to make a company more short
公司决策，使其在
short term profitable that happened to
短期内更加盈利。百
Blockbuster and one of the acts they did
视达就遭遇了这种情况。他们采取的行动之一
was deny John ano's bonus he was the CEO
就是拒绝支付John No的奖金，他是
of Blockbuster
百视达的CEO。是的，
yep and he said you can't do that and
他说你们不能这样做，
they go well we need to we're g to no
他们说，我们必须这样做，不，
we're not going to pay you the bonus
我们不会支付你
previous agreement and so he goes well
之前协议中承诺的奖金。所以他说，好吧，那
in that case I
我就
quit and then they went to find a
辞职了。然后他们去找了
replacement and they brought in a person
接替他的人，他们找了一个人……
who had all of their experience at
他们拥有在
retail stores at convenience
便利
stores and his vision was we have 9,000
店等零售店的所有经验，他的愿景是：我们在全国乃至全世界
stores in almost every community in the
几乎每个社区都有9000家门店，
country in the world why aren't we
为什么我们不
selling gum and clothing and and what
卖口香糖和衣服，而把
are we wasting money on this digital
钱浪费在这些数字
stuff and there's a this is super movie
产品上？接下来我要讲一个超级电影
geeky so pardon me for the
迷的故事，所以请原谅我跑题。
segue um Step Spielberg who I'm sure
斯蒂芬·斯皮尔伯格，我相信
you're familiar with his film school
你们都很熟悉他，他的电影学院
project was a movie about a
项目是一部关于
robot and the robot operates kind of on
机器人的电影，这个机器人的运作方式有点像
a cost benefit analysis and there's the
成本效益分析。
penultimate scene in the movie where the
在电影的倒数第二个场景中，
robot is chasing somebody and he's
机器人正在追逐某人，它越来越近，越来越近，眼看就要抓住
grab the person's ankle and you see the
那个人的脚踝了，你可以看到
sunk cost of the robot's time get to
机器人投入的时间成本已经
break even and he stops and walks away
收回了，就在它抓住那个人的前一刻，它停了下来，转身走开了。这就是百视达的做法，他们
within seconds of grabbing Us by the
差点就抓住我们的脚踝，把我们从梯子上拽下来，然后发生了一些与
something happened unrelated to that and
此无关的事情，
they just turned and walked away and we
他们就这么转身走了，而我们……
just scampered to safety they lost
他们慌忙逃命，失去了
Focus yep so that's there's a lot of
专注力。是的，所以有很多
reasons Netflix Blockbuster didn't go
原因导致Netflix和百视达的
down because of Netflix only
倒闭，这不仅仅是因为Netflix，
but Blockbuster went down because they
百视达的倒闭是因为他们的
had a business model which was very very
商业模式很难
difficult to change and they didn't have
改变，而且他们缺乏
the courage and the persistence to be
勇气和毅力去
willing to do the things that would have
做出
made it change perfect Ted has quite
改变。坦白说，Perfect Ted已经
frankly taken the nation by storm a
席卷全国，这是一种
small green energy drink that you've
你
probably seen popping up to a Tesco or
可能在Tesco或减肥店见过的绿色能量饮料。它
10,000% in a very short period of time
在很短的时间内增长了近10000%，
because people are sick and tired of the
因为人们厌倦了那些
typical unhealthy energy drinks and
不健康的能量饮料，一直
they've been looking for an alternative
在寻找替代品。我现在一边听
I'm sat here during the podcast because
播客一边喝的就是Perfect Ted，因为
it gives me increased focus it doesn't
它能让我更加专注，不会像我那样，在和
podcast and it tastes amazing it's
播客嘉宾进行3、4、5、6个小时的对话后出现能量骤降的情况。而且它的味道也很棒，这正是
exactly what I've been looking for in
我一直在寻找的
terms of energy that's why I'm an
能量饮料，这就是为什么我是Perfect Ted的忠实用户。
investor and that's why they sponsor
投资者，所以他们赞助了
this podcast and for a limited time
这个播客。而且，
perfect ter have given Diary of a CEO
Perfect Ter 限时为《CEO日记》的
listeners only a huge 40% off if you use
听众提供高达 40% 的折扣，只需
the code diary 40 at checkout don't tell
在结账时使用优惠码 diary40 即可。别告诉
anybody about this and you can only get
任何人，而且
this online for a limited time so make
这个优惠只能在线购买，时间有限，千万
sure you don't miss out you left the day
别错过！你
after the IPO in May
在 2002 年 5 月 IPO 的第二天就离开了。IPO 之后，
2002 the IPO happens the company is
公司
valued at a big number um I guess your
估值很高。嗯，我想从那时起你的
life has changed indefinitely from that
生活就发生了翻天覆地的变化，
point because it's a lot of money for
因为对
someone to have um and you go on you
任何人来说，拥有这么多钱都是一笔巨款。然后你
know leave the company for the reasons
离开了公司，原因
you expressed earlier and you go on and
你之前也说过，之后你
do other things and I think at that
去做了其他事情。我认为，在
many others as we sit here in 2024 but
2024 年，流媒体大战实际上已经被 Netflix 和其他许多公司赢得了胜利。但当时，
Blockbuster are effectively dead I think
百视达实际上已经死了，我想
they went oh they went bankrupt what
他们破产了，大概是
eight years after the I didn't they was
八年后吧。
those Wars raged for a while okay so you
那些战争持续了一段时间。好吧，所以
you go public in 2002 right they
你上市了。  2002年，他们
continue pursuing you y um but
继续追查你，但
ultimately they they ran out of steam
最终，
eight years later and go bankrupt in
八年后他们后劲不足，于
2010 you leave Netflix you leave Netflix
2010年破产。你离开了Netflix，你离开了Netflix，
you're a wealthy man you've achieved
你成了一个富翁，你取得了
that almost everybody on planet Earth
地球上几乎所有人都
will never see in terms of
无法企及的
business at that
商业成就。那时，
life uh the day of the IPO I remember we
生活中什么才是最重要的呢？我记得IPO那天，我们
left the trading floor where we had gone
离开了交易大厅，我们在
public New York City my young my son uh
纽约上市。我的儿子，也就是
who actually with me today uh oh yeah in
今天和我在一起的那个人，哦，对了，他当时坐在后面，
the back was was with me he was a young
他还很
much younger man and uh I remember the
年轻。我记得我们俩
two of us sitting in the in the taxi
坐在出租车里，
going downtown in New York we were going
前往纽约市中心，我们打算
to get pizza because I figured he's a
去吃披萨，因为我觉得他是个
California Kid he'd better experience
加州孩子，应该体验一下
New York Pizza uh and I was sitting
纽约披萨。我坐在
there going my life has changed you know
那里，心想我的生活改变了。你知道，
I I do have the option if I want to to
如果我愿意，我可以选择
not have to work again and I be in the
不再工作。我坐在
cab seeing all these people who were
出租车里，看着那些忙碌的人们，心想
going about their lives and going am I
我跟他们有什么
different or not and part of it you then
不同？然后
you realize I like what I do I I'll take
你意识到，我喜欢我所做的事。 我会休息
the day take a day or two but I'm going
一天，一两天，但我还是要回去
to be going back to work I still have
工作。我还有很多
problems to solve we still have to make
问题要解决，我们仍然要让
this company successful and I did I went
这家公司成功。我
back to work and it was not uh it wasn't
回去工作了，情况并没有
as profound that my life changed like
像IPO被推迟那样发生翻天覆地的变化，
all but it's just one more
但这只不过是前进道路上的又一个
Milestone along the way you know Netflix
里程碑。你知道，Netflix还有
still had a lot to do and it it still
很多事情要做，而且确实还有
has a lot to do
很多事情要做。更
um the the more profound thing was was
重要的是，
actually leaving and realizing that I
离开之后，我意识到我可以像
could be as I mentioned before could now
之前提到的那样，
begin spending my days doing the things
开始把时间花在
that I really loved doing and I have
真正热爱的事情上。
I've been incredibly lucky able to do
我非常幸运能够做到这一点。
that you know since leaving Netflix I do
你知道，自从离开Netflix后，我
get to spend every day working with
每天都能和
other early stage companies I did start
其他初创公司一起工作。我在离开
another company after uh Netflix which
Netflix后创办了另一家公司，而且发展得非常
did really really well um I have a great
好。我的
life and I still get a chance to spend
生活很美好，我仍然有机会
time with my family and I still get a
陪伴家人，仍然有
chance to get out and do all the
机会去户外做所有让
outdoors things that make me whole was
我感到充实的事情。
there grief associated with leaving and
离开时会有悲伤吗？
and that's sort of the months after you
那是在离开后的几个月里。
leave is there a grieving process
离开之后会经历一段悲伤期吗？
because
因为
you're surprisingly no there's
令人惊讶的是，并没有。
uncertainty you know I I I've spent most
你知道，会有不确定性。我的大部分
of my professional career in Silicon
职业生涯都在
Valley and as most people there do I
硅谷度过，和那里的大多数人一样，我
know dozens if not hundreds of people
认识几十甚至上百人，他们的
who have economic outcomes there that
经济状况足以
would allow them to not work another day
让他们这辈子都不用工作了。
in their life if they wanted to but it
但
if you do a simple survey of the friends
如果你简单地调查一下
of yours who've been put in that
你那些处于这种
position the vast majority of them go
境地的朋友，你会发现绝大多数人都会重返
back to work they start another
职场，或者创办另一家
company and you realize that we are
公司。你会意识到，我们之所以成为
entrepreneurs not because we have to do
企业家，并非因为我们不得不这样做来
it to earn a living
谋生，而是
we do it because we love that process of
因为我们热爱
solving problems we love that process of
解决问题的过程，热爱
making and building a company we love
创建和发展公司的过程，热爱
that process as I described earlier of
我之前描述的那种与
sitting around the table with really
真正
smart people solving really interesting
聪明的人围坐在桌旁，解决真正有趣的
problems and if success is nothing else
问题的过程。如果说成功还有别的含义，
it's the ability to be able to do the
那就是能够做
kind of things you want to spend your
自己想做的事情，
time doing and doing another company is
而创办另一家公司是
the most thrilling thing in the world
世界上最令人兴奋的事情。
and if I get a chance to do that why
如果我有机会这样做，
wouldn't I want to do that so in that
我为什么不去做呢？所以在离开
period after
之后的那段时间里，
leaving I didn't say I'm retiring I
我没有说我要退休，我
didn't say I'm starting another company
没有。 假设我要创办另一家公司，
I said I'm going to take some time and
我说我会花些时间好好
think about it and in my case I decided
考虑一下。就我而言，
I didn't think I had enemy to start
我当时觉得我没有创办
another company um I was going to spend
另一家公司的动力，我打算把
my time helping other people do it it
时间花在帮助其他人创业上。结果证明
turns out that I was wrong I got sucked
我错了，我被卷入了
into starting another company that's a
另一家公司的创业漩涡中。这完全是
whole another podcast but uh this whole
另一个播客的故事了。但是，这一切与
thing is not about the IPO it's not
IPO无关，与
about success uccess it's not about
成功无关，与
money the thing that makes this the best
金钱无关。这份工作之所以是
job in the world is how cool it is to
世界上最好的工作，是因为它很酷，因为它能让你
take something which hasn't been done
去做一些
before and figure out how to do it and I
以前从未有人做过的事情，并找到实现的方法。我
just feel blessed and I imagine you do
感到非常幸运，我想你也一样。
too and the people you speak to are all
你交谈过的人也都很
blessed that we are allowed to spend our
幸运，我们能够
days doing that one of the things that
每天做这样的事情。多年来，一直
always inspired me and that I've mowed
激励着我、让我敬佩不已的一件事
over for many years is the culture that
是
was created in Netflix because it was so
Netflix创造的企业文化，因为它非常具有
pioneering and it's so sort of spad in
开创性，而且它与
the face of the way that we were told
我们被告知的
things were supposed to be done you know
做事方式截然不同。你知道，
cuz when we when I started my first
因为当我创办第一家
business it was all about family and all
公司时，一切都围绕着家庭和所有的一切。
of this stuff and then I remember that
这些东西，然后我想起了那天
day that I read Netflix's sort of
我读了Netflix的
culture handbook which is quite famous
文化手册，现在很出名，也很
and viral now called freedom and
火，叫做《自由与
responsibility and it was
责任》。它完全
everything that I it was the opposite of
颠覆了我对
everything that I thought a business was
企业
supposed to be you know it was this
应有的认知。你知道，它
radical Freedom that people were given
赋予了人们一种激进的自由，
but then there was a really high bar and
但同时也设定了很高的标准。
I want I've always been curious like
我一直很好奇，第一，这种自由从何而来？
a where did that come from B is that for
第二，这种企业文化模式对
every company is that the right way of
每家公司来说都是正确的吗？
culture um and I guess see what is the
嗯，我想，
the unknown part because we all saw the
未知的部分是什么呢？因为我们都看到了
deck but we don't get to see the actual
演示文稿，但我们看不到实际的
Implement so I'll take your middle part
执行情况。所以我先回答中间部分，也就是
first which is this for everybody and
对所有人而言，
the answer is no um culture as I often
答案是否定的。文化，正如我常
say is not
说的，不是理想化的，而是
observational culture is not something
观察性的。文化不是
that you dream up what you want it to be
你梦想它应该是什么样子，也不是
that you aspire to it to be it's not
你渴望它成为什么样子，更不是
brainstorming what our culture should be
集思广益地讨论我们的文化应该是什么样子，
and now let's print up 40 posters and
然后打印40张海报贴
put them in the
在
breakroom that is not what culture is
休息室里。这不是文化。
culture is how you as the founders
文化是你们这些创始人如何
behave it's how you as the senior
行事，是你们这些高管如何行事。
Executives behave people are watching
观察
you and they're modeling off of you that
你，模仿你，这就是
is what culture is that's where culture
文化，这就是文化的来源。
comes from so if you aren't a certain
所以，如果你不是某种特定的
way you can't have your culture be that
方式，你的文化就不能是那种
way and it's perfectly okay to say that
方式。如果
you behave and want
你真的想以这种方式行事并
to build your company it's entirely
建立公司，那么说我们像一家人完全没问题，这完全
appropriate that's not the way I wanted
合适。但我并不想那样
to behave or build my company so I never
行事或建立公司，所以我从未那样
said that but I'll get to that in just a
说过，稍后我会解释。Netflix 的
minute but it comes from this so this
这种彻底
whole radical honesty thing at Netflix
坦诚的理念源于我
that just came from the way Reed and I
和里德一直以来彼此相待的方式，以及我们
treated our employees the way we wanted
对待员工的方式——我们希望他们以同样的方式
held them accountable to treat their
对待
employees um so it has to come from how
员工，并要求他们也这样做。所以，文化必须源于
you genuinely are um you can police that
你真实的为人。你可以监督，
you can hold each other accountable you
你可以互相监督，你
can say we want to hear from everybody
可以说“我们想听听每个人的意见”，
and then have your HR person pull you
然后让你的人力资源主管
aside after the meeting and go Mark Reed
在会后把你叫到一边，问马克·里德：“
you were always saying you really want
你总是说你想
to hear from everyone of those meetings
听听每个人的意见，但你觉得在那些会议上，有
what percentage of the words do you
多少话是你自己说的？”
think came out of your mouths then and
然后回答：“
go be right Patty we'll do better next
帕蒂，你说得对，我们会做得更好。”
time I you want you want your actions to
下次你希望你的言行一致，这就是
thing of culture is it can't be
文化的核心：它不能是
something alien it means you have to be
外来的东西，这意味着你必须对它
accountable to it because it spreads
负责，因为它会不断传播。
Beyond you that the culture of the first
前
10 people is modeled off first two of
10个人的文化是以你们中的前两个人为榜样，
you the next 90 is off the first 10 the
接下来的90个人以前10个人为榜样，再
next 900 is off that first 100 and so on
接下来的900个人以前100个人为榜样，以此类推。
so if you let it slip if you say our
所以，如果你不小心说漏嘴，比如你说
most one of our principles is no
我们最重要的原则之一是“
unless they're our best
除非是我们最好的
salesperson or the Irreplaceable CFO
销售员或不可替代的首席财务官，否则我们不允许混蛋”，那就
well then then it's different no you've
另当别论了。你
got to be consistent because everyone
必须保持一致，因为每个人都能
sees that anyone with kids knows kids
看到，任何有孩子的人都知道，孩子
don't model what you say they model what
不会模仿你说的话，他们会模仿
you do the other piece this whole
你的行为。另一方面，这种
freedom and responsibility thing is not
自由和责任并不算
novel it's almost every early stage
新鲜事，几乎每个初创
company has this because there's just
公司都会遇到这种情况，因为
aren't the resources to do otherwise you
资源有限。
have let's say 10 people but you have
假设你只有10个人，但你却要完成
the work of a hundred there is not time
100个人的工作，你没有时间
to say okay Stephen here's what you have
告诉他们“好的，斯蒂芬，这是你必须
to do and here's here's what you have to
做的，这是你应该做的”。 你必须
do and check you can't do that you just
做，并且要检查，你不能那样做，你只能说，好吧，这是
go all right here's what I need you see
我需要你做的，看到那边的
that mountain over there I'll meet you
山了吗？
there in two weeks and I need you to
两周后在那里和你碰面，我需要你
have this finished here's what you need
完成这件事。你需要
two weeks meet you there and then I'm
两周时间，在那里和你碰面。然后
not going to talk to you for two weeks
两周内我不会和你说话，
and you're going to have to struggle and
你必须努力奋斗，想办法解决问题，
figure things out and overcome obstacles
克服障碍，
it'll be different things and this
这取决于你要完成的任务，每个人的任务都不一样，
accomplish but I trust that you're going
但我相信你会
stuff done in two weeks that's the
在两周内完成所有事情，到达山顶。这是
responsibility part but I'm giving you
责任部分，但我完全赋予你
the complete Freedom how to get there so
如何完成任务的自由。
that's an easy thing when you have 10
当你有10
people it's a little harder when you
个人的时候，这很容易，当你
have a hundred it's really hard when you
有100个人的时候，就有点难了，当你
have a thousand and the reason is that
有1000个人的时候，就非常难了。原因是，会
happens so get to a point and you're at
发生一些意想不到的事情。当你到达
the mountain and someone shows up like
山顶时，有人
three or four days late and you go oh
迟到了三四天，你会想，哦，
this isn't good I can't have this okay
这可不好，我不能接受。好吧，
from now on I need everyone to give me a
从现在开始，我需要每个人
daily status report so I know in advance
每天向我汇报进度。 所以，如果出现问题，我会提前知道，
if this problems and every person goes
每个人都会说“
oh status
哦，状态
reports okay and now everyone shows up
报告没问题”，现在每个人都
on time but then someone shows up and
准时到岗，但之后有人来了，却发现
they spent too much money and you go oh
他们花的钱太多了，然后你就说“哦，
I can't have this okay everyone I need
我不能接受”，于是你要求所有人
to pre-approve all expenses over
预先审批所有超过
$5,000 and all these people who you're
5000美元的费用。你指望这些人
counting on to be responsible you're
负责任，却把他们当
treating them like an infant you're
婴儿
treat me like an adult that's free and
一样对待。你跟我说：“我给了你这个，你负责一个季度1000万美元的销售额，但我却不相信你能决定住什么样的酒店，或者花多少钱来实现目标。拜托，把我当成年人看待，这是免费的，
responsibility is I I'm going to treat
责任是……我会像对待
you like an adult but most companies do
成年人一样对待你。”但大多数公司都会
is they put these guard rails in place
设置这些限制
to keep people from making errors of
来防止员工犯
judgment and the Netflix experiment is
判断错误，而Netflix的实验则
simply is rather than building guard
截然不同：与其设置
rails to protect ourselves from people
限制来保护自己免受
with bad judgment let's build a
判断力差的人的伤害，不如建立一种
culture where there are no guard rails
没有限制的文化，
and only hire people with good
只雇用判断力好的人。
judgment and that's sit in a nutshell
这就是Netflix的精髓所在。
and you know I'm sure you you've seen
我知道，我相信你…… 看过
the deck but you know you know what the
甲板了，但你知道，你知道
travel policy is there there isn't one
差旅政策是什么吗？根本没有。
you know the expense policy is there
你知道费用政策是什么吗？也
isn't one you know what the vacation
没有。你知道休假
policy is you know there isn't there
政策是什么吗？你知道，根本没有。
aren't any policies the policies are all
所有政策都
summed up as use your best
概括为“运用你的最佳
judgment that's freedom and
判断力”。这就是所谓的自由和
responsibility now that only works if
责任。但这只有在
someone has the judgment to be treated
有人具备相应的判断力并接受这种对待时才有效。
that way so you have to to be diligent
所以你必须认真地
about saying if you don't have the
告诉他们，如果你没有能力
effectively you shouldn't be here but it
有效地做出决定，你就不应该在这里。但事实
turns out there's a magic to this I
证明，这里面有门道。我
company back when I was doing direct
以前在一家大型跨国软件公司工作，当时我在做直
response marketing and um we had a big
复营销。我们有一个像
competitor with like Microsoft and we
微软一样的大型竞争对手。我们
had a big corporate campus and it was
有一个很大的企业园区，非常
beautiful had tennis courts had squash
漂亮，有网球场、壁球
courts it had a big Health Club really
场、一个大型健身俱乐部、一个非常棒的咖啡
wonderful Cafe an Olympic swimming pool
馆、一个奥林匹克游泳池
and a hot
和一个热水
tub and one day myself and Patty McCord
浴缸。有一天，我和Netflix的人力资源主管帕蒂·麦考德（Patty McCord）
walking back from lunch and we saw some
午饭后散步回来，看到一些
of the engineers in the Hut tub and we
工程师在热水浴缸里，我们就过去
swung by to say hello and as we got
打招呼。 走到
close to the hot tub we could tell they
热水浴缸边，我们就能听出来他们
were all bitching about the
都在抱怨
company and we thought it was pretty
公司。我们觉得挺
funny that here they are sitting in this
搞笑的，他们坐在
magnificent hot tub at the the company
公司这么棒的热水浴缸里，居然还在
complaining about it but it triggered
抱怨。但这引发了我们的
this conversation which is if it's not
讨论：如果不是公司
the amenities that make people want to
福利吸引员工，那又是什么呢？
work someplace what is it and the answer
答案
is it's not the fireman pole and the nap
不是消防员滑杆、午睡
pods and the kombucha on tap or any of
舱、现成的康普茶，或者
the other ridiculous thing that people
其他那些人们津津乐道的噱头。而是
throw at it's they want to be treated
他们希望被当作
like adults they want to have agency in
成年人对待，希望在
their life and in their jobs they don't
生活和工作中拥有自主权，不
want to be told what they can and can't
希望被告知什么能做什么不能做什么，
do they want to be given a
他们希望被赋予
clear responsibility and given the
明确的责任，并拥有
freedom to achieve it and that is such a
实现目标的自由。这对
huge unlock for Netflix it's more
Netflix来说至关重要，它
important than how much you pay someone
比你付给员工多少钱
it's more important than almost anything
更重要，几乎比什么都重要。
I have been through this so I my first
我经历过类似的事情，所以我的第一家
business started with the same set of
公司也是从同样的
polic policies and rules especially as
政策和规章制度起步的，尤其是在
it relates like holiday so we've always
假期方面。我们一直都有
had unlimited holiday even in the
无限假期，即使在你
company that you're in you you're part
所在的公司也是如此。你
of now the 40 people that work for the
现在是40人团队的一员。 现在为DERS工作，
ders now we have un limited holiday what
我们有无限假期。
I came to learn interestingly over time
随着时间的推移，我逐渐发现一个有趣的现象：
is that the reason you end up changing
最终改变
these rules is because 5% of people it's
这些规则的原因是，有5%的人——
really like just a few people that don't
实际上只是少数人——缺乏
exercise the Judgment you're talking
你所说的判断力。
about so what you end up doing is going
所以你最终会想，好吧，
okay well I have to change a rule for
我不得不
everybody because of this small group
因为这一小部分人（
maybe three or four people that can't
可能只有三四个人）无法
seem to execute really great judgment
做出真正明智的判断而改变所有人的规则。
and and it's funny cuz I found myself at
这很有趣，因为
one point several times over my career
我职业生涯中好几次都觉得，
going right okay we have to get rid of
好吧，我们必须取消
the unlimited holiday because Tom and
无限假期，因为
Dave and Nigel of 200 people in an
办公室里200人的汤姆、戴夫和奈杰尔根本
office can't make fair and responsible
无法做出公平负责的
judgment and it's kind of just dawned on
判断。但
me as you speaking what what I actually
你刚才说话的时候，我突然意识到，我真正
need to do is just address the three
需要做的，是先解决那三
people you need to fire those people
个人的问题，然后解雇他们。你要反其道而行之，
opposite way you're going to start
开始
looking at all the other policies you
审视你现有的所有其他政策，
have and go I'm going to take get rid of
然后说，我也要取消
those too I'm going to get rid of and
它们。一点一点地取消。
little by little but again it's only if
但前提是，
it has to match how you want the company
这必须符合你希望公司营造的氛围，
to feel it can't be artificial no it is
不能是虚假的。不，
it's always been because I've the reason
它一直都是虚假的。我之所以成为
why I'm an entrepreneur is because I'm
一名企业家，是因为我根本不适合
impossible to employ because I'm I hate
工作，因为我讨厌朝九晚五。
jobs so I tried to create a company
所以我试图创建一个我自己也
where I would want to work in which
想工作的公司。这
means that if you show up late good
意味着，如果你迟到，那很好，
because I'm probably going to be late
因为我可能也会迟到。
too and but the maybe the reason I was
但也许我
late is because I was working late on
迟到的原因就是…… 因为我当时在加班，
something and that actually doesn't
但这其实并不
matter so what time you arrive doesn't
重要。所以你几点到并不
matter it's you know cuz responsible
重要。你知道，
people someone like Jack you haven't got
像杰克这样负责任的人，你不需要
to tell Jack when to work Jack is so
告诉杰克什么时候工作。
focused on the mission Jack will figure
杰克非常专注于任务，
out when he needs to get how and when he
他会自己想办法
needs to get his job done um and you
完成工作。你
don't end up making the rules for people
不会为像
like Jack job at Netflix for you no but
杰克这样的人在Netflix制定规则，但
he's one of those people because he's
他就是这样的人，因为他就像是
like a Founder here he like founded this
这里的创始人之一，他和我一起创立了这个公司，
thing with me so we have that kind of
所以我们有这种
mentality but yeah you're right you end
心态。是的，你说得对，最终你会发现，这很
up making it's so interesting it is it's
有意思。关键在于打破常规。打破常规的
means those three people can't work here
好处是，那三个人不能在这里工作，
but it makes the other 97 really want to
但这会让其他97个人更想来
work there it makes other people because
这里工作。因为
most places don't do that it's like uh
大多数地方都不会这样做，所以，
doesn't make it I don't care when you
我不在乎你什么时候
work I don't care what hours you work I
工作，不在乎你工作几个小时，
don't care whether you're home or in the
不在乎你是否在家。 或者在
office I do care that once we've agreed
办公室里，我确实很在意，一旦我们商定了
what responsibilities you have that you
你的职责，你就应该把
achieve get those things done and if you
这些事情做好。如果你
can do it in six hours a week because
每周只需六小时就能完成，因为
you're so smart and
你如此聪明能干，那当然
talented all power to you the last thing
最好。
I wanted to talk to you about is
我最后想跟你聊的是，
actually something that I read on on
我在
LinkedIn which went viral which was you
LinkedIn上看到一篇很火的文章，你
talking about your relationship with
谈到了你和
your wife and your commitment to date
妻子的关系，以及你们每周
night on Tuesdays right the post went
二晚上坚持约会的习惯。这篇文章之所以
viral because I think it struck a cord
火，是因为我觉得它触动了
with a lot of people who have really
很多
burnt themselves out because of their
因为
job what is that principle you have with
工作而筋疲力尽的人。你和妻子之间有什么原则？
your wife and how long have you kept it
你坚持了多久了？对了，
for so right when I was you know in my
我二十多岁的时候，
late 20s I was working like a dog I was
工作非常拼命，总是加班加点，
working all the time nights weekends and
晚上和周末也不休息。这并不是
not cuz I had a slave dropper boss but
因为我的老板是个奴隶，而是
because I CU I loved what I was doing
因为我热爱我的工作，
I just was totally into it and I was in
我完全投入其中。
a relationship at the time with the
当时我正和我
woman who's now my wife and it kind of
现在的妻子谈恋爱。
slowly dawned on me perhaps with a
慢慢地，或许在
little bit of help from her that this
她的一些提醒下，我意识到，这种工作方式
wasn't as satisfactory for her as it was
对她来说并不像对我一样令人满意。 这
for me and it kind of made me realize
让我意识到，
that if I really wanted to have a
如果我真的想要一段
sustainable long-term relationship I had
可持续的长期关系，我必须想办法解决。
that I realized that I had to have more
我意识到我必须
balance in my life uh and we began this
在生活中找到更多平衡。于是我们开始实行一项
policy of saying I'm not I'm going to
政策：我不会把和
girlfriend and who's now my wife and
女朋友（现在是我的妻子）的关系放在首位。这项政策有很
that has taken a lot of forms but the
多种形式，但
one that I referred to was I had this
我提到的是，我在Netflix工作
policy at Netflix before Netflix after
前后都实行过一项政策：
Netflix that every
每周
Tuesday uh I'd leave work at 5:00 sharp
二，我准时五点下班。
my wife would get a sitter or before we
我的妻子会找保姆，或者在我们
had kids we' just go out and we'd spend
有孩子之前，我们会出去约会，
the evening together had a date night
共度夜晚。
and this was
这条原则是：
sacren that I don't care what's going on
不管发生什么，
I'm leaving at 5 um if there's a crisis
我都会在五点准时离开。如果有什么紧急情况，我们会在五点前解决。
we're going to wrap it up by five if you
如果你
have to talk to me well we're going to
必须和我说话，我们可以在去
talk in the way to the car but I'm
车的路上谈，但我
leaving at 5: and um it was kind of
五点准时离开。这很
remarkable because after a while uh
神奇，因为过了一段时间后，晚上
crisis stopped happening after o00 on
五点以后就再也没有发生过紧急情况了。
Tuesday and all of a sudden people were
周二，突然间，人们都能在
after 5:00 on Tuesday but there was a
周二下午5点之后解决自己的问题了。但还有一个
secondary benefit which is that I did
次要的好处，那就是我之前一直在强调
balance that I didn't want this to be
平衡的重要性。我不希望它
all encompassing that there were other
占据生活的全部，因为
aspects to what was important everyone's
每个人的
lives and by modeling this I was walking
生活中还有其他重要的事情。通过以身作则，我证明了这一点，也表明了
um you could run a company and have a
你实际上可以经营一家公司并拥有一段
relationship and it wasn't easy this is
感情。这并不容易，毕竟这是
a startup so a lot of times you know i'
一家创业公司。很多时候，你知道，我约会
have date night we get back late and I'd
回来很晚，然后晚上
10 o'clock or uh a lot of times I'd come
10点又得回办公室。或者很多时候，我
home have dinner with my kids go back
回家和孩子们吃完晚饭后，还要回去
and work for a couple hours but I carved
工作几个小时。但我还是会抽出
out the time to be present and do those
时间来陪伴他们，做这些
things and in my life um it's maybe even
事情。在我的生活中，这或许更具
a bit more challenging a startups are
挑战性。创业很
hard and I have a family but I also have
辛苦，我还要照顾家庭，但我对
this passion for outdoor stuff you know
户外运动充满热情。你知道，
I love Backcountry skiing and climbing
我喜欢野外滑雪、攀岩、
and kaying and mountaineering all this
皮划艇和登山，所有这些
stuff that's really hard to do between
运动都很难在
your five o'clock call and your 7
五点钟的时间里完成。 凌晨三点的电话和七点的
o'clock meeting so I had a really
会议，所以我真的努力
structure my life in a way that I could
安排好自己的生活，这样才能
have meaningful time in all three of
在这三个方面都拥有有意义的时间。
these areas of my life and it's been
这真的非常非常
really really hard was there a risk of
难。有没有可能
losing the relationship at some point
失去这段感情？有，可能在我……
yeah probably when I was in the my right
嗯，大概就是那个时候，我……嗯，我……我到底在干什么？
I I was becoming clear she was going I'm
我开始明白她的意思了，她说“我
not going to put up with this you know
不会再忍受了，你知道，
if you're not going to be here for me
如果你不在我身边，那这一切还有什么意义？”
what's the point how did you take that
你一开始是怎么想的？非常
first very sobering I mean it really
清醒。我的意思是，这真的
makes you think how important is this to
会让你思考，这段感情对我来说到底有多重要。
me um and I know some people might say
我知道有些人可能会说它
it's not that important my what my work
没那么重要，我的工作
is the most important thing it's the
才是最重要的，是
only thing that's important to me I
我唯一重要的事情。但我改变了想法，我认为……
that um that having a relationship was
拥有一段感情
important to me and more importantly
对我来说很重要，更重要的是，
that I thought it was probably possible
我认为
that I could do
我或许可以兼顾
both um again it's part of the running
两者。嗯，这就像是在奔跑，而
not running for planes it's saying I
不是在赶飞机。我的意思是，我
don't need to be there all the time I
不需要一直待在那里，我
can prioritize well I can
可以分清轻重缓急。嗯，我可以……
um uh distribute work to other people I
嗯，把工作分配给其他人，我
can make this work and not only that not
可以做到。不仅如此，
only can I do the work and have the
我不仅可以工作，还能维系
relationship with my wife and my family
和妻子家人的关系。
I can get out and do outdoor stuff which
我还能出去做些户外活动，这正是
is what I need to make myself
我保持身心健康所需要的。
whole and listen this is a great way for
听着，这对我来说是一个很好的总结方式。
me to wrap this in a way but you know
你知道，
I've had a amazing entrepreneurial
我的创业
career as I you know I've had six seven
生涯非常精彩，我创办过六七家
companies depending upon how you count
公司（具体数量取决于你怎么算），其中三家公司上市，
it I've had a three IPOs you know two
两家是市值数
multi-billion dollar companies so proud
十亿美元的公司，我为此感到自豪。
of that but um way more proud of the
但是，更让我自豪的是，
fact that I managed to do all that while
我做到这一切的同时，还能和
staying married to the same woman while
同一个女人保持婚姻关系，让
having my kids grow up knowing me and as
我的孩子们在成长过程中了解我，而且据我所知，他们也喜欢我。我
best I can tell liking me um and still
还能
getting out to Backcountry ski mountain
去野外滑雪、骑山地
bike uh and all the things that I need
自行车，做所有那些让
to make me whole and that I'm proud of
我身心健康的事情，这些都让我感到自豪。从
in the grand scheme of your
你的
happiness you've got your business
幸福的角度来看，你有你的事业，你
Endeavors you've got your fantastic
有你和
relationships with your wife and your
妻子
family what does matter more oh it's a
家人之间美好的关系，那么什么更重要呢？哦，这是一个
trick question I mean it's so I guess
陷阱问题，我的意思是，它确实是。所以我想
I'll answer in the counterintuitive way
我会回答的。 从反直觉的角度来看，
way you need all
你需要这
three you know I I think had I said had
三者。你知道，我想如果我说，如果我
my wife said some ultimatum like I need
妻子下了最后通牒，比如“我必须
to quit and you know you were going to
辞职，然后你
move to Montana and you're going to be a
搬去蒙大拿州，去当
mailman and and we'll have a great I
邮递员，我们会过上美好的生活”，我会很不
would have been unhappy and I mean I've
开心。我的意思是，我们
had a great relationship but she knows
关系一直很好，但她知道
that she knows I can't turn this off I
我无法停止工作，我无法停止。
about seeing problems and wanting to fix
看到问题，想要解决
them and having to pick one and say
它们，却不得不选择其中一个，然后说“这就是
that's all I'm going to do that's no
我唯一要做的事”，这根本不是
life either um that's why I think you
生活。嗯，这就是为什么我想，你
know again before we started you said
知道，在我们开始之前，你问我
what do you what's your big focus and I
你最关注的是什么，我
said
说
balance uh I think about it every day I
平衡。嗯，我每天都在思考这个问题，
think about it every week they're all
每周都在思考，它们都很
important and I do what I have to do to
重要，我会尽我所能去实现它。
make that happen Mark we have a closing
马克，我们播客有个结尾的
tradition on the podcast where the last
传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，而下一位嘉宾
guest not knowing who they're leaving it
并不知道问题会留给谁。
for and the question that was left for
留给
you is what in your life were you most
你的问题是：你一生中最大的
wrong about and what did you learn from
错误是什么？ 你从中吸取教训了吗？
it uh
嗯，
so one of my big regrets is I mentioned
我最大的遗憾之一就是，我
before that I had all this Magazine
之前提到过，我有很多杂志
subscription
订阅方面的
experience uh I knew circulation I knew
经验，我了解发行，了解
the subscription business and it took me
订阅业务，但我花了
more than almost two years to figure out
将近两年时间才意识到，
that maybe we could use this stupid
也许我们可以把这套东西用
thing for Netflix and I think of all the
在 Netflix 上。想想我们
time and all the money that we wasted
浪费了那么多时间和金钱，
because I never even occurred to me to
因为我之前根本没想到这一点。天哪，我真想狠狠地
try that and God I wish I could kick
抽
myself and go back and say for God's
自己一巴掌，回到过去，对自己说：看在上帝的份上，早点
sake try this sooner try this sooner
试试！早点试试！事后诸葛亮真是个
hindsight's a wonderful thing it is
好东西，不是吗？
isn't it and it fills you with wonderful
它能让你汲取宝贵的
lessons and wisdom and all of that
经验和智慧，而所有这些
wisdom has been encapsulated in this
智慧都浓缩在这本
wonderful book that will never work in
精彩的书里。这本书以
various ways as you go through the
各种方式展现了你在
Journey of founding Netflix but also the
创立 Netflix 的历程，以及你
life that's lived in amongst those pages
人生经历中积累的感悟。
it's one of the most interesting
它是
fascinating Timeless books I've read
我读过的最有趣、最引人入胜、最经久不衰的书之一，
because it's about true principles the
因为它讲述的是真正的原则，
true principles from your father from
来自你父亲的教诲，来自
your journey and from everything you've
你的人生旅程，来自你一路走来所
learned along the way so thank you so
学到的一切。所以，马克，非常感谢你
much for writing such an incredible book
写了这么一本精彩的书。嗯，
Mark um I'll link it down below it's
我会在下面附上链接。 它
called that will never work the birth of
叫做《这永远不会奏效：Netflix 的诞生
Netflix and the amazing life of an idea
与一个想法的奇妙人生》，
and thank you so much for the work you
非常感谢你
do for entrepreneurs across all your
通过你的所有
social channels across your your work
社交渠道、你的工作
and your mentorship because it really is
以及你的指导为创业者所做的一切，因为你
um looking back down the ladder and
回顾过往，
helping pull other people up with your
用你的智慧帮助其他人向上攀登，
wisdom and that's an incredibly
这真的是一件非常
incredibly generous thing for you to do
非常慷慨的事情，所以
so thank you so much Mark thanks Stephen
非常感谢你，马克，谢谢斯蒂芬。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦